<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <string name="contact">Contact</string>
  <string name="contactLichess">Contact Lichess</string>
  <string name="whatCanWeHelpYouWith">What can we help you with?</string>
  <string name="visitThisPage">Visit this page to solve the issue</string>
  <string name="iCantLogIn">I can\'t log in</string>
  <string name="noConfirmationEmail">I didn\'t receive my confirmation email</string>
  <string name="forgotPassword">I forgot my password</string>
  <string name="forgotUsername">I forgot my username</string>
  <string name="youCanLoginWithEmail">You can login with the email address you signed up with</string>
  <string name="lost2FA">I lost access to my two-factor authentication codes</string>
  <string name="doPasswordReset">Complete a password reset to remove your second factor</string>
  <string name="accountSupport">I need account support</string>
  <string name="wantTitle">I want my title displayed on Lichess</string>
  <string name="visitTitleConfirmation">To show your title on your Lichess profile, and participate in Titled Arenas, visit the title confirmation page</string>
  <string name="wantCloseAccount">I want to close my account</string>
  <string name="closeYourAccount">You can close your account on this page</string>
  <string name="doNotAskByEmail">Do not ask us by email to close an account, we won\'t do it.</string>
  <string name="wantReopen">I want to reopen my account</string>
  <string name="reopenOnThisPage">You can reopen your account on this page. It only works once.</string>
  <string name="doNotAskByEmailToReopen">Do not ask us by email to reopen an account, we won\'t do it.</string>
  <string name="wantChangeUsername">I want to change my username</string>
  <string name="changeUsernameCase">Visit this page to change the case of your username</string>
  <string name="cantChangeMore">We can\'t change more than the case. For technical reasons, it\'s downright impossible.</string>
  <string name="orCloseAccount">However, you can close your current account, and create a new one.</string>
  <string name="wantClearHistory">I want to clear my history or rating</string>
  <string name="cantClearHistory">It\'s not possible to clear your game history, puzzle history, or ratings.</string>
  <string name="wantReport">I want to report a player</string>
  <string name="toReportAPlayerUseForm">To report a player, use the report form</string>
  <string name="youCanAlsoReachReportPage">You can also reach that page by clicking the %s report button on a profile page.</string>
  <string name="doNotReportInForum">Do not report players in the forum.</string>
  <string name="doNotSendReportEmails">Do not send us report emails.</string>
  <string name="doNotMessageModerators">Please do not send direct messages to moderators.</string>
  <string name="onlyReports">Only reporting players through the report form is effective.</string>
  <string name="wantReportBug">I want to report a bug</string>
  <string name="reportBugInForum">In the Lichess Feedback section of the forum</string>
  <string name="reportWebsiteIssue">As a Lichess website issue on GitHub</string>
  <string name="reportMobileIssue">As a Lichess mobile app issue on GitHub</string>
  <string name="reportBugInDiscord">In the Lichess Discord server</string>
  <string name="howToReportBug">Please describe what the bug looks like, what you expected to happen instead, and the steps to reproduce the bug.</string>
  <string name="illegalPawnCapture" comment="Appears as an option for reasons to contact Lichess on the 'contact' page: https://lichess.org/contact#help-enpassant&#10;&#10;Players used to routinely write to Lichess stating that there was a bug, or that the other player had hacked their game in some way. In actuality, the player was using the legal move of en passant.&#10;&#10;Please translate this string from the perspective of the player who would be selecting this contact option, and call it 'Illegal', even though we know this is a legal move.">Illegal pawn capture</string>
  <string name="calledEnPassant">It is called \"en passant\" and is one of the rules of chess.</string>
  <string name="tryEnPassant">Try this little interactive game to learn more about \"en passant\".</string>
  <string name="illegalCastling">Illegal or impossible castling</string>
  <string name="castlingPrevented">Castling is only prevented if the king goes through a controlled square.</string>
  <string name="castlingRules">Make sure you understand the castling rules</string>
  <string name="tryCastling">Try this little interactive game to practice castling in chess</string>
  <string name="castlingImported">If you imported the game, or started it from a position, make sure you correctly set the castling rights.</string>
  <string name="insufficientMaterial">Insufficient mating material</string>
  <string name="fideMate">According to the FIDE Laws of Chess ยง6.9, if a checkmate is possible with any legal sequence of moves, then the game is not a draw</string>
  <string name="knightMate">It is possible to checkmate with only a knight or a bishop, if the opponent has more than a king on the board.</string>
  <string name="noRatingPoints">No rating points were awarded</string>
  <string name="ratedGame">Make sure you played a rated game. Casual games do not affect the players\' ratings.</string>
  <string name="botRatingAbuse">In certain circumstances when playing against a bot account, a rated game may not award points if it is determined that the player is abusing the bot for rating points.</string>
  <string name="errorPage">Error page</string>
  <string name="reportErrorPage">If you faced an error page, you may report it:</string>
  <string name="learnHowToMakeBroadcasts">Learn how to make your own broadcasts on Lichess</string>
  <string name="banAppeal">Appeal for a ban or IP restriction</string>
  <string name="engineAppeal">Engine or cheat mark</string>
  <string name="sendAppealTo">You may send an appeal to %s.</string>
  <string name="falsePositives">False positives do happen sometimes, and we\'re sorry about that.</string>
  <string name="ifLegit">If your appeal is legitimate, we will lift the ban ASAP.</string>
  <string name="accountLost">However if you indeed used engine assistance, even just once, then your account is unfortunately lost.</string>
  <string name="doNotDeny">Do not deny having cheated. If you want to be allowed to create a new account, just admit to what you did, and show that you understood that it was a mistake.</string>
  <string name="otherRestriction">Other restriction</string>
  <string name="collaboration">Collaboration, legal, commercial</string>
  <string name="monetizing">Monetizing Lichess</string>
  <string name="buyingLichess">Buying Lichess</string>
  <string name="authorizationToUse">Authorization to use Lichess</string>
  <string name="welcomeToUse">You are welcome to use Lichess for your activity, even commercial.</string>
  <string name="videosAndBooks">You can show it in your videos, and you can print screenshots of Lichess in your books.</string>
  <string name="creditAppreciated">Credit is appreciated but not required.</string>
  <string name="noneOfTheAbove">None of the above</string>
  <string name="sendEmailAt">Send us an email at %s.</string>
  <string name="explainYourRequest">Please explain your request clearly and thoroughly. State your Lichess username, and any information that could help us help you.</string>
</resources>
