<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <string name="advancedPawn">Advanced pawn</string>
  <string name="advancedPawnDescription">One of your pawns is deep into the opponent position, maybe threatening to promote.</string>
  <string name="advantage">Advantage</string>
  <string name="advantageDescription">Seize your chance to get a decisive advantage. (200cp ≤ eval ≤ 600cp)</string>
  <string name="anastasiaMate">Anastasia\'s mate</string>
  <string name="anastasiaMateDescription">A knight and rook or queen team up to trap the opposing king between the side of the board and a friendly piece.</string>
  <string name="arabianMate">Arabian mate</string>
  <string name="arabianMateDescription">A knight and a rook team up to trap the opposing king on a corner of the board.</string>
  <string name="attackingF2F7">Attacking f2 or f7</string>
  <string name="attackingF2F7Description">An attack focusing on the f2 or f7 pawn, such as in the fried liver opening.</string>
  <string name="attraction">Attraction</string>
  <string name="attractionDescription">An exchange or sacrifice encouraging or forcing an opponent piece to a square that allows a follow-up tactic.</string>
  <string name="backRankMate">Back rank mate</string>
  <string name="backRankMateDescription">Checkmate the king on the home rank, when it is trapped there by its own pieces.</string>
  <string name="balestraMate">Balestra mate</string>
  <string name="balestraMateDescription">A bishop delivers the checkmate, while a queen blocks the remaining escape squares</string>
  <string name="blindSwineMate">Blind Swine mate</string>
  <string name="blindSwineMateDescription">Two rooks team up to mate the king in an area of 2 by 2 squares.</string>
  <string name="bishopEndgame">Bishop endgame</string>
  <string name="bishopEndgameDescription">An endgame with only bishops and pawns.</string>
  <string name="bodenMate">Boden\'s mate</string>
  <string name="bodenMateDescription">Two attacking bishops on criss-crossing diagonals deliver mate to a king obstructed by friendly pieces.</string>
  <string name="castling">Castling</string>
  <string name="castlingDescription">Bring the king to safety, and deploy the rook for attack.</string>
  <string name="capturingDefender">Capture the defender</string>
  <string name="capturingDefenderDescription">Removing a piece that is critical to defense of another piece, allowing the now undefended piece to be captured on a following move.</string>
  <string name="cornerMate">Corner mate</string>
  <string name="crushing">Crushing</string>
  <string name="crushingDescription">Spot the opponent blunder to obtain a crushing advantage. (eval ≥ 600cp)</string>
  <string name="discoveredCheck">Discovered check</string>
  <string name="discoveredCheckDescription">Move a piece to reveal a check from a hidden attacking piece, which often leads to a decisive advantage.</string>
  <string name="doubleBishopMate">Double bishop mate</string>
  <string name="doubleBishopMateDescription">Two attacking bishops on adjacent diagonals deliver mate to a king obstructed by friendly pieces.</string>
  <string name="dovetailMate">Dovetail mate</string>
  <string name="dovetailMateDescription">A queen delivers mate to an adjacent king, whose only two escape squares are obstructed by friendly pieces.</string>
  <string name="equality">Equality</string>
  <string name="equalityDescription">Come back from a losing position, and secure a draw or a balanced position. (eval ≤ 200cp)</string>
  <string name="kingsideAttack">Kingside attack</string>
  <string name="kingsideAttackDescription">An attack of the opponent\'s king, after they castled on the king side.</string>
  <string name="clearance">Clearance</string>
  <string name="clearanceDescription">A move, often with tempo, that clears a square, file or diagonal for a follow-up tactical idea.</string>
  <string name="defensiveMove">Defensive move</string>
  <string name="defensiveMoveDescription">A precise move or sequence of moves that is needed to avoid losing material or another advantage.</string>
  <string name="deflection">Deflection</string>
  <string name="deflectionDescription">A move that distracts an opponent piece from another duty that it performs, such as guarding a key square. Sometimes also called \"overloading\".</string>
  <string name="discoveredAttack">Discovered attack</string>
  <string name="discoveredAttackDescription">Moving a piece that previously blocked an attack by another long range piece, such as a knight out of the way of a rook.</string>
  <string name="doubleCheck">Double check</string>
  <string name="doubleCheckDescription">Checking with two pieces at once, as a result of a discovered attack where both the moving piece and the unveiled piece attack the opponent\'s king.</string>
  <string name="endgame">Endgame</string>
  <string name="endgameDescription">A tactic during the last phase of the game.</string>
  <string name="enPassantDescription">A tactic involving the en passant rule, where a pawn can capture an opponent pawn that has bypassed it using its initial two-square move.</string>
  <string name="exposedKing">Exposed king</string>
  <string name="exposedKingDescription">A tactic involving a king with few defenders around it, often leading to checkmate.</string>
  <string name="fork">Fork</string>
  <string name="forkDescription">A move where the moved piece attacks two opponent pieces at once.</string>
  <string name="hangingPiece">Hanging piece</string>
  <string name="hangingPieceDescription">A tactic involving an opponent piece being undefended or insufficiently defended and free to capture.</string>
  <string name="hookMate">Hook mate</string>
  <string name="hookMateDescription">Checkmate with a rook, knight, and pawn along with one enemy pawn to limit the enemy king\'s escape.</string>
  <string name="interference">Interference</string>
  <string name="interferenceDescription">Moving a piece between two opponent pieces to leave one or both opponent pieces undefended, such as a knight on a defended square between two rooks.</string>
  <string name="intermezzo">Intermezzo</string>
  <string name="intermezzoDescription">Instead of playing the expected move, first interpose another move posing an immediate threat that the opponent must answer. Also known as \"Zwischenzug\" or \"In between\".</string>
  <string name="killBoxMate">Kill box mate</string>
  <string name="killBoxMateDescription">A rook is next to the enemy king and supported by a queen that also blocks the king\'s escape squares. The rook and the queen catch the enemy king in a 3 by 3 \"kill box\".</string>
  <string name="triangleMate">Triangle mate</string>
  <string name="triangleMateDescription">The queen and rook, one square away from the enemy king, are on the same rank or file, separated by one square, forming a triangle.</string>
  <string name="vukovicMate">Vukovic mate</string>
  <string name="vukovicMateDescription">A rook and knight team up to mate the king. The rook delivers mate while supported by a third piece, and the knight is used to block the king\'s escape squares.</string>
  <string name="knightEndgame">Knight endgame</string>
  <string name="knightEndgameDescription">An endgame with only knights and pawns.</string>
  <string name="long">Long puzzle</string>
  <string name="longDescription">Three moves to win.</string>
  <string name="master">Master games</string>
  <string name="masterDescription">Puzzles from games played by titled players.</string>
  <string name="masterVsMaster">Master vs Master games</string>
  <string name="masterVsMasterDescription">Puzzles from games between two titled players.</string>
  <string name="mate">Checkmate</string>
  <string name="mateDescription">Win the game with style.</string>
  <string name="mateIn1">Mate in 1</string>
  <string name="mateIn1Description">Deliver checkmate in one move.</string>
  <string name="mateIn2">Mate in 2</string>
  <string name="mateIn2Description">Deliver checkmate in two moves.</string>
  <string name="mateIn3">Mate in 3</string>
  <string name="mateIn3Description">Deliver checkmate in three moves.</string>
  <string name="mateIn4">Mate in 4</string>
  <string name="mateIn4Description">Deliver checkmate in four moves.</string>
  <string name="mateIn5">Mate in 5 or more</string>
  <string name="mateIn5Description">Figure out a long mating sequence.</string>
  <string name="middlegame">Middlegame</string>
  <string name="middlegameDescription">A tactic during the second phase of the game.</string>
  <string name="oneMove">One-move puzzle</string>
  <string name="oneMoveDescription">A puzzle that is only one move long.</string>
  <string name="opening">Opening</string>
  <string name="openingDescription">A tactic during the first phase of the game.</string>
  <string name="pawnEndgame">Pawn endgame</string>
  <string name="pawnEndgameDescription">An endgame with only pawns.</string>
  <string name="pin">Pin</string>
  <string name="pinDescription">A tactic involving pins, where a piece is unable to move without revealing an attack on a higher value piece.</string>
  <string name="promotion">Promotion</string>
  <string name="promotionDescription">Promote one of your pawns to a queen or minor piece.</string>
  <string name="queenEndgame">Queen endgame</string>
  <string name="queenEndgameDescription">An endgame with only queens and pawns.</string>
  <string name="queenRookEndgame">Queen and Rook</string>
  <string name="queenRookEndgameDescription">An endgame with only queens, rooks, and pawns.</string>
  <string name="queensideAttack">Queenside attack</string>
  <string name="queensideAttackDescription">An attack of the opponent\'s king, after they castled on the queen side.</string>
  <string name="quietMove">Quiet move</string>
  <string name="quietMoveDescription">A move that does not make a check or capture, but does prepare an unavoidable threat for a later move.</string>
  <string name="rookEndgame">Rook endgame</string>
  <string name="rookEndgameDescription">An endgame with only rooks and pawns.</string>
  <string name="sacrifice">Sacrifice</string>
  <string name="sacrificeDescription">A tactic involving giving up material in the short-term, to gain an advantage again after a forced sequence of moves.</string>
  <string name="short">Short puzzle</string>
  <string name="shortDescription">Two moves to win.</string>
  <string name="skewer">Skewer</string>
  <string name="skewerDescription">A motif involving a high value piece being attacked, moving out the way, and allowing a lower value piece behind it to be captured or attacked, the inverse of a pin.</string>
  <string name="smotheredMate">Smothered mate</string>
  <string name="smotheredMateDescription">A checkmate delivered by a knight in which the mated king is unable to move because it is surrounded (or smothered) by its own pieces.</string>
  <string name="superGM">Super GM games</string>
  <string name="superGMDescription">Puzzles from games played by the best players in the world.</string>
  <string name="trappedPiece">Trapped piece</string>
  <string name="trappedPieceDescription">A piece is unable to escape capture as it has limited moves.</string>
  <string name="underPromotion">Underpromotion</string>
  <string name="underPromotionDescription">Promotion to a knight, bishop, or rook.</string>
  <string name="veryLong">Very long puzzle</string>
  <string name="veryLongDescription">Four moves or more to win.</string>
  <string name="xRayAttack">X-Ray attack</string>
  <string name="xRayAttackDescription">A piece attacks or defends a square, through an enemy piece.</string>
  <string name="zugzwang">Zugzwang</string>
  <string name="zugzwangDescription">The opponent is limited in the moves they can make, and all moves worsen their position.</string>
  <string name="mix">Healthy mix</string>
  <string name="mixDescription">A mix of everything. You don\'t know what to expect, so you remain ready for anything! Just like in real games.</string>
  <string name="playerGames">Player games</string>
  <string name="playerGamesDescription">Lookup puzzles generated from your games, or from another player\'s games.</string>
  <string name="puzzleDownloadInformation">These puzzles are in the public domain, and can be downloaded from %s.</string>
</resources>
