<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="faqAbbreviation">Často kladené dotazy (FAQ)</string>
	<string name="frequentlyAskedQuestions">Často kladené otázky</string>
	<string name="whyIsLishogiCalledLishogi">Proč se Lishogi nazývá Lishogi?</string>
	<string name="forkedFromLichess">Lishogi je projekt s otevřeným zdrojovým kódem vycházející z liShessu, ale protože je určen k hraní shogi, nazývá se lishogi.</string>
	<string name="lishogiCombinationLiveLightLibrePronounced">Protože je to odvozeno od Liсhess. A Liсhess se nazývá Liсhess, protože je to kombinace live (živě)/light (lehkého)/libre (zdarma) a šachu. Lishogi se vyslovuje %1$s</string>
	<string name="leeshogi">lee-shogi</string>
	<string name="whyLiveLightLibre">Živé, protože hry jsou hrány a sledovány v reálném čase 24/7; lehké a volné, protože Lishogi má otevřený zdrojový kód a je nezatížené proprietárním nepořádkem, který zaplavuje ostatní weby.</string>
	<string name="whyIsLilaCalledLila">Similarly, the source code for Lishogi, %1$s, stands for li[shogi in sca]la, seeing as the bulk of Lishogi is written in %2$s, an intuitive programming language.</string>
	<string name="howCanIContributeToLishogi">How can I contribute to Lishogi?</string>
	<string name="lishogiPoweredByDonationsAndVolunteers">Lishogi is powered by donations from patrons and the efforts of a team of volunteers.</string>
	<string name="beingAPatron">Staňte se patronem</string>
	<string name="otherWaysToContribute">Here are many other ways you could contribute to Lishogi.</string>
	<string name="breakdownOfOurCosts">rozložení našich nákladů</string>
	<string name="otherWaysToHelp">další způsoby jak pomoci</string>
	<string name="fairPlay">Férová hra</string>
	<string name="whyFlaggedRatingManipulationOrCheater">Proč jsem podezřelý z manipulování s ratingem (úmyslné prohry a vnější pomoc) nebo z hraní za pomoci umělé intelegince?</string>
	<string name="cheatDetectionMethods">Lishogi má silné metody detekce a velmi důkladný postup pro přezkoumání všech důkazů a rozhodování. Tento proces často zahrnuje mnoho moderátorů a může trvat delší dobu. V jednotlivých případech nebudeme s důvody rozhodnutí zacházet do podrobností o důkazech nebo rozhodovacím procesu. Takový postup by v budoucnu usnadnil obcházení detekcí a byl by pozvánkou k neproduktivním diskusím. Tento čas a úsilí je lépe využit na jiné důležité věci. Uživatelé se mohou odvolat e-mailem %1$s, ale rozhodnutí se zřídka mění.</string>
	<string name="whenAmIEligibleRatinRefund">Kdy mám nárok na automatické vrácení hodnocení za zápasy s podvodníky?</string>
	<string name="ratingRefundExplanation">Jednu minutu poté, co je hráč označen, vezmeme jejich posledních 40 hodnocených her za uplynulé 3 dny. Pokud jste proti němu v těchto hrách hráli, ztratili jste body (kvůli prohře nebo remíze) a vaše hodnocení nebylo prozatimní, budou vám body vráceny. Počet vrácených bodů je omezen v závislosti na vašem dosavadním nejlepším hodnocení a rovněž vývoji vašeho hodnocení po dané hře.
 (Například pokud se vaše hodnocení po těchto hrách mezitím výrazně zvyšovalo, je možné, že nedostanete nazpátek žádné body, a nebo jen jejich část.) Maximálně vám můžeme vrátit 150 bodů.</string>
	<string name="preventLeavingGameWithoutResigning">Co děláte s hráči, kteří opouštějí rozehrané hry, aniž by se vzdali?</string>
	<string name="leavingGameWithoutResigningExplanation">Hráčům, kteří často přerušují nebo ukončují hry, bude dočasně zakázáno hrát. Tato informace není veřejně uvedena na jejich profilu. Pokud v tomto chování pokračují, délka zákazu se prodlužuje a nakonec jim může být úplně uzavřen účet.</string>
	<string name="howCanIBecomeModerator">Jak se mohu stát moderátorem?</string>
	<string name="youCannotApply">Není možné žádat o funkci moderátora. Pokud uvidíme někoho, o němž si myslíme, že by byl dobrým moderátorem, přímo jej kontaktujeme.</string>
	<string name="isCorrespondenceDifferent">Je korespondenční hra jiná než normální shogi?</string>
	<string name="youCanUseOpeningBookNoEngine">Na Lishogi je hlavní rozdílem v pravidlech pro korespondenční šachy to, že je povoleno otevřít nápovědní knihu. Použití počítačových programů pro rady je stále zakázáno a bude mít za následek označení hry za hru s pomocí. Přestože ICCF povoluje použití počítačových programů v korespondenčním šachu, Lishogi ne.</string>
	<string name="gameplay">Hraní hry</string>
	<string name="howBulletBlitzEtcDecided">How are Bullet, Blitz and other time controls decided?</string>
	<string name="basedOnGameDuration">Lishogi time controls are based on estimated game duration = %1$s
For instance, the estimated duration of a 5+3|4 game is 60 × 5 + 60 × 3 + 25 × 4 = 580 seconds.</string>
	<string name="formulaOfDuration">60 × (clock initial time in minutes) + 60 × (clock increment) + 25 × (clock byoyomi) × (clock periods)</string>
	<string name="inferiorThanXsEqualYtimeControl">&lt; %1$ss = %2$s</string>
	<string name="superiorThanXsEqualYtimeControl">≥ %1$ss = %2$s</string>
	<string name="whatVariantsCanIplay">Jaké varianty mohu hrát na Lishogi?</string>
	<string name="lishogiSupportShogiAnd">Lishogi supports standard shogi and %1$s.</string>
	<string name="whatIsACPL">Co je to průměrná pěšcová ztráta (angl. \"average centipawn loss\")?</string>
	<string name="acplExplanation">V šachu se jako jednotka síly jednotlivých tahů ve srovnání s nejlepšími možnými tahy doporučenými počítačem používá tzv. centipawn (z angličtiny). Jeden centipawn je ekvivalentní jedné setině hodnoty pěšáka. To znamená, že 100 centipawnů odpovídá jednomu pěšákovi.

Nejlepší tah doporučený počítačem ztrácí 0 centipawnů (z definice). Slabší tah povede na zhoršení pozice, a právě toto zhoršení pozice se měří v centipawnech.

Tato hodnota se používá pro ověření kvality hry. Čím nižší má hráč pěšcovou ztrátu, tím silnější tahy hraje.

Počítačová analýza na Lishogi využívá program Stockfish. Hráčovi tahy jsou tedy porovnávány vůči tahům, které by zahrál Stockfish.</string>
	<string name="insufficientMaterial">Prohrávání na čas, remízování a nedostatečný materiál</string>
	<string name="goodIntroduction">dobré zahájení</string>
	<string name="officialRulesPDF">official rules (PDF)</string>
	<string name="lishogiTraining">Trénink Lishogi</string>
	<string name="fourfoldRepetition">Fourfold repetition</string>
	<string name="handBookPDF">handbook (PDF)</string>
	<string name="notRepeatedMoves">We did not repeat moves. Why was the game still drawn by repetition?</string>
	<string name="repeatedPositionsThatMatters">Fourfold repetition is about repeated %1$s, not moves. Repetition does not have to occur consecutively.</string>
	<string name="positions">pozice</string>
	<string name="configure">nastavit</string>
	<string name="accounts">Účty</string>
	<string name="titlesAvailableOnLishogi">Jaké tituly jsou na Lishogi?</string>
	<string name="showYourTitle">If you have an OTB title, you can apply to have this displayed on your account by completing the %1$s, including a clear image of an identifying document/card and a selfie of you holding the document/card.

Verifying as a titled player on Lishogi gives access to play in the Titled Arena events.

Finally there is an honorary %2$s title.</string>
	<string name="verificationForm">formulář pro ověření</string>
	<string name="canIbecomeLM">Can I get the Lishogi Master (LM) title?</string>
	<string name="noUpperCaseDot">Ne.</string>
	<string name="lMtitleComesToYouDoNotRequestIt">This honorific title is unofficial and only exists on Lishogi.

We rarely award it to highly notable players who are good citizens of Lishogi, at our discretion. You don\'t get the LM title, the LM title gets to you. If you qualify, you will get a message from us regarding it and the choice to accept or decline.

Do not ask for the LM title.</string>
	<string name="whatUsernameCanIchoose">Co může být moje uživatelské jméno?</string>
	<string name="usernamesNotOffensive">In general, usernames should not be: offensive, impersonating someone else, or advertising. You can read more about the %1$s.</string>
	<string name="guidelines">guidelines</string>
	<string name="uniqueTrophies">Unique trophies</string>
	<string name="ownerUniqueTrophies">That trophy is unique in the history of Lishogi, nobody other than %1$s will ever have it.</string>
	<string name="aHourlyBulletTournament">a hourly Bullet tournament</string>
	<string name="lishogiRatings">Lishogi hodnocení</string>
	<string name="whichRatingSystemUsedByLishogi">Jaký systém hodnocení Lishogi využívá?</string>
	<string name="ratingSystemUsedByLishogi">Ratings are calculated using the Glicko-2 rating method developed by Mark Glickman. This is a very popular rating method, and is used by a significant number of chess organisations (FIDE being a notable counter-example, as they still use the dated Elo rating system).

Fundamentally, Glicko ratings use \"confidence intervals\" when calculating and representing your rating. When you first start using the site, your rating starts at 1500 ± 700. The 1500 represents your rating, and the 700 represents the confidence interval.

Basically, the system is 90% sure that your rating is somewhere between 800 and 2200. It is incredibly uncertain. Because of this, when a player is just starting out, their rating will change very dramatically, potentially several hundred points at a time. But after some games against established players the confidence interval will narrow, and the amount of points gained/lost after each game will decrease.

Another point to note is that, as time passes, the confidence interval will increase. This allows you to gain/lose points points more rapidly to match any changes in your skill level over that time.</string>
	<string name="whatIsProvisionalRating">Why is there a question mark (?) next to a rating?</string>
	<string name="provisionalRatingExplanation">The question mark means the rating is provisional. Reasons include:</string>
	<string name="notPlayedEnoughRatedGamesAgainstX">The player has not yet finished enough rated games against %1$s in the rating category.</string>
	<string name="similarOpponents">opponents of similar strength</string>
	<string name="notPlayedRecently">The player hasn\'t played enough recent games. Depending on the number of games you\'ve played, it might take around a year of inactivity for your rating to become provisional again.</string>
	<string name="ratingDeviationMorethanOneHundredTen">Concretely, it means that the Glicko-2 deviation is greater than 110. The deviation is the level of confidence the system has in the rating. The lower the deviation, the more stable is a rating.</string>
	<string name="howDoLeaderoardsWork">How do ranks and leaderboards work?</string>
	<string name="inOrderToAppearsYouMust">In order to get on the %1$s you must:</string>
	<string name="ratingLeaderboards">rating leaderboard</string>
	<string name="havePlayedMoreThanThirtyGamesInThatRating">have played at least 30 rated games in a given rating,</string>
	<string name="havePlayedARatedGameAtLeastOneWeekAgo">have played a rated game within the last week for this rating,</string>
	<string name="ratingDeviationLowerThanXinShogiYinVariants">have a rating deviation lower than %1$s, in standard shogi, and lower than %2$s in variants,</string>
	<string name="beInTopTen">be in the top 10 in this rating.</string>
	<string name="secondRequirementToStopOldPlayersTrustingLeaderboards">The 2nd requirement is so that players who no longer use their accounts stop populating leaderboards.</string>
	<string name="whyAreRatingHigher">Why are ratings different compared to other sites and organisations such as 81Dojo and Shogi Club 24?</string>
	<string name="whyAreRatingHigherExplanation">It is best not to think of ratings as absolute numbers, or compare them against other organisations. Different organisations have different levels of players, different rating systems (Elo, Glicko, Glicko-2, or a modified version of the aforementioned). These factors can drastically affect the absolute numbers (ratings).

It\'s best to think of ratings as \"relative\" figures (as opposed to \"absolute\" figures): Within a pool of players, their relative differences in ratings will help you estimate who will win/draw/lose, and how often. Saying \"I have X rating\" means nothing unless there are other players to compare that rating to.</string>
	<string name="howToHideRatingWhilePlaying">How to hide ratings while playing?</string>
	<string name="enableZenMode">Enable Zen-mode in the %1$s, or by pressing %2$s during a game.</string>
	<string name="displayPreferences">display preferences</string>
	<string name="connexionLostCanIGetMyRatingBack">I lost a game due to lag/disconnection. Can I get my rating points back?</string>
	<string name="weCannotDoThatEvenIfItIsServerSideButThatsRare">Unfortunately, we cannot give back rating points for games lost due to lag or disconnection, regardless of whether the problem was at your end or our end. The latter is very rare though. Also note that when Lishogi restarts and you lose on time because of that, we abort the game to prevent an unfair loss.</string>
	<string name="howToThreeDots">How to...</string>
	<string name="enableDisableNotificationPopUps">Enable or disable notification popups?</string>
	<string name="viewSiteInformationPopUp">View site information popup</string>
	<string name="lishogiCanOptionnalySendPopUps">Lishogi can optionally send popup notifications, for example when it is your turn or you received a private message.

Click the lock icon next to the lishogi.org address in the URL bar of your browser.

Then select whether to allow or block notifications from Lishogi.</string>
</resources>
