<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <string name="faqAbbreviation">FAQ</string>
  <string name="frequentlyAskedQuestions">Frequently Asked Questions</string>
  <string name="whyIsLichessCalledLichess">Why is Lichess called Lichess?</string>
  <string name="lichessCombinationLiveLightLibrePronounced">Lichess is a combination of live/light/libre and chess. It is pronounced %1$s.</string>
  <string name="leechess">lee-chess</string>
  <string name="hearItPronouncedBySpecialist">Hear it pronounced by an expert.</string>
  <string name="whyLiveLightLibre">Live, because games are played and watched in real-time 24/7; light and libre for the fact that Lichess is open-source and unencumbered by proprietary junk that plagues other websites.</string>
  <string name="whyIsLilaCalledLila">Similarly, the source code for Lichess, %1$s, stands for li[chess in sca]la, seeing as the bulk of Lichess is written in %2$s, an intuitive programming language.</string>
  <string name="howCanIContributeToLichess">How can I contribute to Lichess?</string>
  <string name="lichessPoweredByDonationsAndVolunteers">Lichess is powered by donations from patrons and the efforts of a team of volunteers.</string>
  <string name="findMoreAndSeeHowHelp">You can find out more about %1$s (including a %2$s). If you want to help Lichess by volunteering your time and skills, there are many %3$s.</string>
  <string name="beingAPatron">being a patron</string>
  <string name="breakdownOfOurCosts">breakdown of our costs</string>
  <string name="otherWaysToHelp">other ways to help</string>
  <string name="areThereWebsitesBasedOnLichess">Are there websites based on Lichess?</string>
  <string name="yesLichessInspiredOtherOpenSourceWebsites">Yes. Lichess has indeed inspired other open-source sites that use our %1$s, %2$s, or %3$s.</string>
  <string name="keyboardShortcuts">What keyboard shortcuts are there?</string>
  <string name="keyboardShortcutsExplanation">Some Lichess pages have keyboard shortcuts you can use. Try pressing the \'?\' key on a study, analysis, puzzle, or game page to list available keyboard shortcuts.</string>
  <string name="fairPlay">Fair Play</string>
  <string name="whenAmIEligibleRatinRefund">When am I eligible for the automatic rating refund from cheaters?</string>
  <string name="ratingRefundExplanation">One minute after a player is marked, their 40 latest rated games in the last 5 days are taken. If you were their opponent in one of those games, you lost rating (because of a loss or a draw), and your rating was not provisional, you get a rating refund. The refund is capped based on your peak rating and your rating progress after the game. (For example, if your rating greatly increased after that game, you might get no refund or only a partial refund.) A refund will never exceed 150 points.</string>
  <string name="preventLeavingGameWithoutResigning">What is done about players leaving games without resigning?</string>
  <string name="leavingGameWithoutResigningExplanation">If your opponent frequently aborts/leaves games, they get \"play banned\", which means they\'re temporarily banned from playing games. This is not publicly indicated on their profile. If this behavior continues, the length of the playban increases - and prolonged behavior of this nature may lead to account closure.</string>
  <string name="howCanIBecomeModerator">How can I become a moderator?</string>
  <string name="youCannotApply">It is not possible to apply to become a moderator. If we see someone who we think would be good as a moderator, we will contact them directly.</string>
  <string name="isCorrespondenceDifferent">Is correspondence different from normal chess?</string>
  <string name="pleaseReadFairPlayPage">For more information, please read our %s</string>
  <string name="fairPlayPage">fair play page</string>
  <string name="youCanUseOpeningBookNoEngine">On Lichess, the main difference in rules for correspondence chess is that an opening book is allowed. The use of engines is still prohibited and will result in being flagged for engine assistance. Although ICCF allows engine use in correspondence, Lichess does not.</string>
  <string name="gameplay">Gameplay</string>
  <string name="howBulletBlitzEtcDecided">How are Bullet, Blitz and other time controls decided?</string>
  <string name="basedOnGameDuration">Lichess time controls are based on estimated game duration = %1$s.
For instance, the estimated duration of a 5+3 game is 5 × 60 + 40 × 3 = 420 seconds.</string>
  <string name="durationFormula">(clock initial time in seconds) + 40 × (clock increment)</string>
  <string name="inferiorThanXsEqualYtimeControl">≤ %1$ss = %2$s</string>
  <string name="superiorThanXsEqualYtimeControl">≥ %1$ss = %2$s</string>
  <string name="whatVariantsCanIplay">What variants can I play on Lichess?</string>
  <string name="lichessSupportChessAnd">Lichess supports standard chess and %1$s.</string>
  <string name="eightVariants">8 chess variants</string>
  <string name="whatIsACPL">What is the average centipawn loss (ACPL)?</string>
  <string name="acplExplanation">The centipawn is the unit of measure used in chess as representation of the advantage. A centipawn is equal to 1/100th of a pawn. Therefore 100 centipawns = 1 pawn. These values play no formal role in the game but are useful to players, and essential in computer chess, for evaluating positions.

The top computer move will lose zero centipawns, but lesser moves will result in a deterioration of the position, measured in centipawns.

This value can be used as an indicator of the quality of play. The fewer centipawns one loses per move, the stronger the play.

The computer analysis on Lichess is powered by Stockfish.</string>
  <string name="insufficientMaterial">Losing on time, drawing and insufficient material</string>
  <string name="lichessFollowFIDErules">In the event of one player running out of time, that player will usually lose the game. However, the game is drawn if the position is such that the opponent cannot checkmate the player\'s king by any possible series of legal moves (%1$s).

In rare cases this can be difficult to decide automatically (forced lines, fortresses). By default we always side with the player who did not run out of time.

Note that it can be possible to mate with a single knight or bishop if the opponent has a piece that could block the king.</string>
  <string name="fideHandbook">FIDE handbook</string>
  <string name="fideHandbookX">FIDE handbook %s</string>
  <string name="discoveringEnPassant">Why can a pawn capture another pawn when it is already passed? (en passant)</string>
  <string name="explainingEnPassant">This is a legal move known as \"en passant\". The Wikipedia article gives a %1$s.

It is described in sections 3.7.3.1 and 3.7.3.2 of the %2$s:

\"A pawn occupying a square on the same rank as and on an adjacent file to an opponent’s pawn which has just advanced two squares in one move from its original square may capture this opponent’s pawn as though the latter had been moved only one square. This capture is only legal on the move following this advance and is called an ‘en passant’ capture.\"

See the %3$s on this move for some practice with it.</string>
  <string name="goodIntroduction">good introduction</string>
  <string name="lichessTraining">Lichess training</string>
  <string name="watchIMRosenCheckmate">Watch International Master Eric Rosen checkmate %s.</string>
  <string name="threefoldRepetition">Threefold repetition</string>
  <string name="threefoldRepetitionExplanation">If a position occurs three times, players can claim a draw by %1$s. Lichess implements the official FIDE rules, as described in Article 9.2 of the %2$s.</string>
  <string name="threefoldRepetitionLowerCase">threefold repetition</string>
  <string name="notRepeatedMoves">We did not repeat moves. Why was the game still drawn by repetition?</string>
  <string name="repeatedPositionsThatMatters">Threefold repetition is about repeated %1$s, not moves. Repetition does not have to occur consecutively.</string>
  <string name="positions">positions</string>
  <string name="weRepeatedthreeTimesPosButNoDraw">We repeated a position three times. Why was the game not drawn?</string>
  <string name="threeFoldHasToBeClaimed">Repetition needs to be claimed by one of the players. You can do so by pressing the button that is shown or by offering a draw before your final repeating move. It won\'t matter if your opponent rejects the draw offer, the threefold repetition draw will be claimed anyway. You can also %1$s Lichess to automatically claim repetitions for you. Additionally, fivefold repetition always immediately ends the game.</string>
  <string name="configure">configure</string>
  <string name="accounts">Accounts</string>
  <string name="titlesAvailableOnLichess">What titles are there on Lichess?</string>
  <string name="lichessRecognizeAllOTBtitles">Lichess recognizes all FIDE titles gained from OTB (over the board) play, as well as %1$s. Here is a list of FIDE titles:</string>
  <string name="showYourTitle">If you have an OTB title, you can apply to have this displayed on your account by completing the %1$s, including a clear image of an identifying document/card and a selfie of you holding the document/card.

Verifying as a titled player on Lichess gives access to play in the Titled Arena events.

Finally there is an honorary %2$s title.</string>
  <string name="asWellAsManyNMtitles">many national master titles</string>
  <string name="verificationForm">verification form</string>
  <string name="canIbecomeLM">Can I get the Lichess Master (LM) title?</string>
  <string name="noUpperCaseDot">No.</string>
  <string name="lMtitleComesToYouDoNotRequestIt">This honorific title is unofficial and only exists on Lichess.

We rarely award it to highly notable players who are good citizens of Lichess, at our discretion. You don\'t get the LM title, the LM title gets to you. If you qualify, you will get a message from us regarding it and the choice to accept or decline.

Do not ask for the LM title.</string>
  <string name="whatUsernameCanIchoose">What can my username be?</string>
  <string name="usernamesNotOffensive">In general, usernames should not be: offensive, impersonating someone else, or advertising. You can read more about the %1$s.</string>
  <string name="guidelines">guidelines</string>
  <string name="canIChangeMyUsername">Can I change my username?</string>
  <string name="usernamesCannotBeChanged">No, usernames cannot be changed for technical and practical reasons. Usernames are materialized in too many places: databases, exports, logs, and people\'s minds. You can adjust the capitalization once.</string>
  <string name="uniqueTrophies">Unique trophies</string>
  <string name="ownerUniqueTrophies">That trophy is unique in the history of Lichess; nobody other than %1$s will ever have it.</string>
  <string name="aHourlyBulletTournament">an hourly Bullet tournament</string>
  <string name="goldenZeeExplanation">ZugAddict was streaming and for the last 2 hours he had been trying to defeat A.I. level 8 in a 1+0 game, without success. Thibault told him that if he successfully did it on stream, he\'d get a unique trophy. One hour later, he smashed Stockfish, and the promise was honored.</string>
  <string name="lichessRatings">Lichess ratings</string>
  <string name="whichRatingSystemUsedByLichess">What rating system does Lichess use?</string>
  <string name="ratingSystemUsedByLichess">Ratings are calculated using the Glicko-2 rating method developed by Mark Glickman. This is a very popular rating method, and is used by a significant number of chess organisations (FIDE being a notable counter-example, as they still use the dated Elo rating system).

Fundamentally, Glicko ratings use \"confidence intervals\" when calculating and representing your rating. When you first start using the site, your rating starts at 1500 ± 1000. The 1500 represents your rating, and the 1000 represents the confidence interval.

Basically, the system is 95% sure that your rating is somewhere between 500 and 2500. It is incredibly uncertain. Because of this, when a player is just starting out, their rating will change very dramatically, potentially several hundred points at a time. But after some games against established players the confidence interval will narrow, and the amount of points gained/lost after each game will decrease.

Another point to note is that, as time passes, the confidence interval will increase. This allows you to gain/lose points more rapidly to match any changes in your skill level over that time.</string>
  <string name="whatIsProvisionalRating">Why is there a question mark (?) next to a rating?</string>
  <string name="provisionalRatingExplanation">The question mark means the rating is provisional. Reasons include:</string>
  <string name="notPlayedEnoughRatedGamesAgainstX">The player has not yet finished enough rated games against %1$s in the rating category.</string>
  <string name="similarOpponents">opponents of similar strength</string>
  <string name="notPlayedRecently">The player hasn\'t played enough recent games. Depending on the number of games you\'ve played, it might take around a year of inactivity for your rating to become provisional again.</string>
  <string name="ratingDeviationMorethanOneHundredTen">Concretely, it means that the Glicko-2 deviation is greater than 110. The deviation is the level of confidence the system has in the rating. The lower the deviation, the more stable a rating is.</string>
  <string name="howDoLeaderoardsWork">How do ranks and leaderboards work?</string>
  <string name="inOrderToAppearsYouMust">In order to get on the %1$s you must:</string>
  <string name="ratingLeaderboards">rating leaderboard</string>
  <string name="havePlayedMoreThanThirtyGamesInThatRating">have played at least 30 rated games in a given rating,</string>
  <string name="havePlayedARatedGameAtLeastOneWeekAgo">have played a rated game within the last week for this rating,</string>
  <string name="ratingDeviationLowerThanXinChessYinVariants">have a rating deviation lower than %1$s, in standard chess, and lower than %2$s in variants,</string>
  <string name="beInTopTen">be in the top 10 in this rating.</string>
  <string name="secondRequirementToStopOldPlayersTrustingLeaderboards">The 2nd requirement is so that players who no longer use their accounts stop populating leaderboards.</string>
  <string name="whyAreRatingHigher">Why are ratings higher compared to other sites and organisations such as FIDE, USCF and the ICC?</string>
  <string name="whyAreRatingHigherExplanation">It is not useful to think of ratings as absolute numbers, or compare them against other organisations. Different organisations have different levels of players, different rating systems (Elo, Glicko, Glicko-2, or a modified version of the aforementioned). These factors can drastically affect the absolute numbers (ratings).

It is useful to think of ratings as \"relative\" figures (as opposed to \"absolute\" figures): Within a pool of players, their relative differences in ratings will help you estimate who will win/draw/lose, and how often. Saying \"I have X rating\" means nothing unless there are other players to compare that rating to.</string>
  <string name="howToHideRatingWhilePlaying">How to hide ratings while playing?</string>
  <string name="enableZenMode">Enable Zen-mode in the %1$s, or by pressing %2$s during a game.</string>
  <string name="displayPreferences">display preferences</string>
  <string name="connexionLostCanIGetMyRatingBack">I lost a game due to lag/disconnection. Can I get my rating points back?</string>
  <string name="weCannotDoThatEvenIfItIsServerSideButThatsRare">Unfortunately, we cannot give back rating points for games lost due to lag or disconnection, regardless of whether the problem was at your end or our end. The latter is very rare though. Also note that when Lichess restarts and you lose on time because of that, we abort the game to prevent an unfair loss.</string>
  <string name="howToThreeDots">How to...</string>
  <string name="enableDisableNotificationPopUps">Enable or disable notification popups?</string>
  <string name="viewSiteInformationPopUp">View site information popup</string>
  <string name="lichessCanOptionnalySendPopUps">Lichess can optionally send popup notifications, for example when it is your turn or you received a private message.

Click the lock icon next to the lichess.org address in the URL bar of your browser.

Then select whether to allow or block notifications from Lichess.</string>
  <string name="enableAutoplayForSoundsQ">Enable autoplay for sounds?</string>
  <string name="enableAutoplayForSoundsA">Most browsers can prevent sound from playing on a freshly loaded page to protect users. Imagine if every website could immediately bombard you with audio ads.

The red mute icon appears when your browser prevents lichess.org from playing a sound. Usually this restriction is lifted once you click something. On some mobile browsers, touch dragging a piece does not count as a click. In that case you must tap the board to allow sound at the start of each game.

We show the red icon to alert you when this happens. Often you can explicitly allow lichess.org to play sounds. Here are instructions for doing so on recent versions of some popular browsers.</string>
  <string name="desktop">desktop</string>
  <string name="enableAutoplayForSoundsFirefox">1. Go to lichess.org
2. Press Ctrl-i on Linux/Windows or cmd-i on MacOS
3. Click the Permissions tab
4. Allow Audio and Video on lichess.org</string>
  <string name="enableAutoplayForSoundsChrome">1. Go to lichess.org
2. Click the lock icon in the address bar
3. Click Site Settings
4. Allow Sound</string>
  <string name="enableAutoplayForSoundsSafari">1. Go to lichess.org
2. Click Safari in the menu bar
3. Click Settings for lichess.org ...
4. Allow All Auto-Play</string>
  <string name="enableAutoplayForSoundsMicrosoftEdge">1. Click the three dots in the top right corner
2. Click Settings
3. Click Cookies and Site Permissions
4. Scroll down and click Media autoplay
5. Add lichess.org to Allow</string>
  <string name="stopMyselfFromPlaying">Stop myself from playing?</string>
  <string name="mentalHealthCondition">stand-alone mental health condition</string>
  <string name="lichessUserstyles">Lichess userstyles</string>
  <string name="fewerLobbyPools">fewer lobby pools</string>
  <string name="adviceOnMitigatingAddiction">We regularly receive messages from users seeking help with playing too much.

While Lichess doesn’t ban or block players except for Terms of Service violations, we recommend using external tools to limit excessive playing behavior. Some common suggestions for website blockers include %1$s, %2$s, and %3$s. If you want to keep using the site but not be tempted by fast time controls, you also might be interested in %4$s; here is one with %5$s.

Some players may feel their playing habits are turning into an addiction. The WHO classifies gaming disorder as a %6$s, with essential characteristics of 1) impaired control over gaming, 2) increasing priority given to gaming, and 3) escalation of gaming despite negative consequences. If you think your chess playing behavior follows this pattern, we encourage you to speak with a friend or family member and/or a professional.</string>
</resources>
