<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="faqAbbreviation">FAQ</string>
	<string name="frequentlyAskedQuestions">Mga Madalas na Itinatanong</string>
	<string name="whyIsLishogiCalledLishogi">Bakit tinawag na Lishogi ang Lishogi?</string>
	<string name="forkedFromLichess">Ang Lishogi ay isang open source na project galing sa lichess, ngunit dahil ito ay para sa paglalaro ng shogi, ito ay tinawag na lishogi.</string>
	<string name="lishogiCombinationLiveLightLibrePronounced">Dahil ito ay galing sa Lichess. At ang Lichess ay tinawag na Lichess dahil ito ay isang combinasyon ng live/light/libre at chess. Ang Lishogi ay binibigkas nang ganito: %1$s.</string>
	<string name="leeshogi">lee-shogi</string>
	<string name="whyLiveLightLibre">Live, dahil ang mga laro ay linalaro at pinapanood ng totoong oras 24/7, at libre para sa katotohanang ang Lishogi ay bukas-mapagkukunan at hindi nababalutan ng pagmamay-ari ng basura na nagpapahamak sa iba pang mga website.</string>
	<string name="whyIsLilaCalledLila">Similarly, the source code for Lishogi, %1$s, stands for li[shogi in sca]la, seeing as the bulk of Lishogi is written in %2$s, an intuitive programming language.</string>
	<string name="howCanIContributeToLishogi">Paano ako makakapag-ambag sa Lishogi?</string>
	<string name="lishogiPoweredByDonationsAndVolunteers">Ang Lishogi ay napapagana ng mga donasyon galing sa mga patron at mga pagsisikap ng isang grupo ng mga volunteers.</string>
	<string name="beingAPatron">Maging isang patron</string>
	<string name="otherWaysToContribute">Here are many other ways you could contribute to Lishogi.</string>
	<string name="breakdownOfOurCosts">breakdown of our costs</string>
	<string name="otherWaysToHelp">iba pang paraan upang makatulong</string>
	<string name="fairPlay">Fair Play</string>
	<string name="whyFlaggedRatingManipulationOrCheater">Bakit ako hinudyatan ng artipisyal na pagmamanipula ng rating (sandbagging o boosting) o kaya naman ay paggamit ng tulong ng isang kompyuter?</string>
	<string name="cheatDetectionMethods">Ang Lishogi ay mayroong malalakas na paraan ng detection at masusing proseso sa pagsusuri ng lahat ng mga ebidensiya at paggawa ng desisyon. Ang proseso ay kadalasang may maraming mga moderator at maaaring maging matagal ang proseso. Maliban sa mismong marka, hindi kami pupunta nang malalim sa mga detalye tungkol sa mga ebidensiya o ang paggawa ng desisyon sa mga indibidwal na mga kaso. Kung ginawa namin ito\'y mas magiging madali iwasan ang detection sa hinaharap, at magiging imbitasyon sa mga debate na walang mga bunga. Ang oras at pagsisikap na iyon ay mas mabuti na gamitin sa iba pang mas importante na mga kaso. Ang mga user ay maaaring mag-apela sa pamamagitan ng pag-email sa %1$s, ngunit karamihan ng mga desisyon ay kadalasang hindi na binabago.</string>
	<string name="whenAmIEligibleRatinRefund">When am I eligible for the automatic rating refund from cheaters?</string>
	<string name="ratingRefundExplanation">One minute after a player is marked, their 40 latest rated games in the last 3 days are taken. If you are their opponent in those games, you lost rating (because of a loss or a draw), and your rating was not provisional, you get a rating refund. The refund is capped based on your peak rating and your rating progress after the game.
  (For example, if your rating greatly increased after those games, you might get no refund or only a partial refund.) A refund will never exceed 150 points.</string>
	<string name="preventLeavingGameWithoutResigning">What is done about players leaving games without resigning?</string>
	<string name="leavingGameWithoutResigningExplanation">If your opponent frequently aborts/leaves games, they get \"play banned\", which means they\'re temporarily banned from playing games. This is not publically indicated on their profile. If this behaviour continues, the length of the playban increases - and prolonged behaviour of this nature may lead to account closure.</string>
	<string name="howCanIBecomeModerator">How can I become a moderator?</string>
	<string name="youCannotApply">It’s not possible to apply to become a moderator. If we see someone who we think would be good as a moderator, we will contact them directly.</string>
	<string name="isCorrespondenceDifferent">Is correspondence different from normal shogi?</string>
	<string name="youCanUseOpeningBookNoEngine">On Lishogi, the main difference in rules for correspondence shogi is that an opening book is allowed. The use of engines is still prohibited and will result in being flagged for engine assistance. Although ICCF allows engine use in correspondence, Lishogi does not.</string>
	<string name="gameplay">Gameplay</string>
	<string name="howBulletBlitzEtcDecided">How are Bullet, Blitz and other time controls decided?</string>
	<string name="basedOnGameDuration">Lishogi time controls are based on estimated game duration = %1$s
For instance, the estimated duration of a 5+3|4 game is 60 × 5 + 60 × 3 + 25 × 4 = 580 seconds.</string>
	<string name="formulaOfDuration">60 × (clock initial time in minutes) + 60 × (clock increment) + 25 × (clock byoyomi) × (clock periods)</string>
	<string name="inferiorThanXsEqualYtimeControl">&lt; %1$ss = %2$s</string>
	<string name="superiorThanXsEqualYtimeControl">≥ %1$ss = %2$s</string>
	<string name="whatVariantsCanIplay">Anong mga variant ang pwede kong laruin sa Lishogi?</string>
	<string name="lishogiSupportShogiAnd">Lishogi supports standard shogi and %1$s.</string>
	<string name="whatIsACPL">What is the average centipawn loss (ACPL)?</string>
	<string name="acplExplanation">The centipawn is the unit of measure used in chess as representation of the advantage. A centipawn is equal to 1/100th of a pawn. Therefore 100 centipawns = 1 pawn. These values play no formal role in the game but are useful to players, and essential in computer chess, for evaluating positions.

The top computer move will lose zero centipawns, but lesser moves will result in a deterioration of the position, measured in centipawns.

This value can be used as an indicator of the quality of play. The fewer centipawns one loses per move, the stronger the play.

The computer analysis on Lishogi is powered by YaneuraOu and Fairy-Stockfish.</string>
	<string name="insufficientMaterial">Losing on time, drawing and insufficient material</string>
	<string name="goodIntroduction">magandang introduksyon</string>
	<string name="officialRulesPDF">opisyal na mga panuntunan (PDF)</string>
	<string name="lishogiTraining">Lishogi training</string>
	<string name="fourfoldRepetition">Fourfold repetition</string>
	<string name="handBookPDF">handbook (PDF)</string>
	<string name="notRepeatedMoves">We did not repeat moves. Why was the game still drawn by repetition?</string>
	<string name="repeatedPositionsThatMatters">Fourfold repetition is about repeated %1$s, not moves. Repetition does not have to occur consecutively.</string>
	<string name="positions">Mga posisyon</string>
	<string name="configure">configure</string>
	<string name="accounts">Accounts</string>
	<string name="titlesAvailableOnLishogi">What titles are there on Lishogi?</string>
	<string name="showYourTitle">If you have an OTB title, you can apply to have this displayed on your account by completing the %1$s, including a clear image of an identifying document/card and a selfie of you holding the document/card.

Verifying as a titled player on Lishogi gives access to play in the Titled Arena events.

Finally there is an honorary %2$s title.</string>
	<string name="verificationForm">verification form</string>
	<string name="canIbecomeLM">Maaari ko bang makuha ang titulong Lishogi Master (LM)?</string>
	<string name="noUpperCaseDot">Hindi.</string>
	<string name="lMtitleComesToYouDoNotRequestIt">This honorific title is unofficial and only exists on Lishogi.

We rarely award it to highly notable players who are good citizens of Lishogi, at our discretion. You don\'t get the LM title, the LM title gets to you. If you qualify, you will get a message from us regarding it and the choice to accept or decline.

Do not ask for the LM title.</string>
	<string name="whatUsernameCanIchoose">Ano ang pwedeng maging username ko?</string>
	<string name="usernamesNotOffensive">Sa pangkalahatan, ang mga username ay hindi dapat nakakasakit sa iba, nagpapanggap bilang ibang tao, o isang advertisement. Maaari na basahin pa nang higit tungkol sa %1$s.</string>
	<string name="guidelines">mga patnubay</string>
	<string name="uniqueTrophies">Mga natatanging mga tropeo</string>
	<string name="ownerUniqueTrophies">That trophy is unique in the history of Lishogi, nobody other than %1$s will ever have it.</string>
	<string name="aHourlyBulletTournament">a hourly Bullet tournament</string>
	<string name="lishogiRatings">Mga Lishogi rating</string>
	<string name="whichRatingSystemUsedByLishogi">Anong uri ng rating system ang ginagamit ng Lishogi?</string>
	<string name="ratingSystemUsedByLishogi">Ratings are calculated using the Glicko-2 rating method developed by Mark Glickman. This is a very popular rating method, and is used by a significant number of chess organisations (FIDE being a notable counter-example, as they still use the dated Elo rating system).

Fundamentally, Glicko ratings use \"confidence intervals\" when calculating and representing your rating. When you first start using the site, your rating starts at 1500 ± 700. The 1500 represents your rating, and the 700 represents the confidence interval.

Basically, the system is 90% sure that your rating is somewhere between 800 and 2200. It is incredibly uncertain. Because of this, when a player is just starting out, their rating will change very dramatically, potentially several hundred points at a time. But after some games against established players the confidence interval will narrow, and the amount of points gained/lost after each game will decrease.

Another point to note is that, as time passes, the confidence interval will increase. This allows you to gain/lose points points more rapidly to match any changes in your skill level over that time.</string>
	<string name="whatIsProvisionalRating">Bakit may tandang pananong (?) sa tabi ng isang rating?</string>
	<string name="provisionalRatingExplanation">The question mark means the rating is provisional. Reasons include:</string>
	<string name="notPlayedEnoughRatedGamesAgainstX">The player has not yet finished enough rated games against %1$s in the rating category.</string>
	<string name="similarOpponents">opponents of similar strength</string>
	<string name="notPlayedRecently">The player hasn\'t played enough recent games. Depending on the number of games you\'ve played, it might take around a year of inactivity for your rating to become provisional again.</string>
	<string name="ratingDeviationMorethanOneHundredTen">Concretely, it means that the Glicko-2 deviation is greater than 110. The deviation is the level of confidence the system has in the rating. The lower the deviation, the more stable is a rating.</string>
	<string name="howDoLeaderoardsWork">How do ranks and leaderboards work?</string>
	<string name="inOrderToAppearsYouMust">In order to get on the %1$s you must:</string>
	<string name="ratingLeaderboards">rating leaderboard</string>
	<string name="havePlayedMoreThanThirtyGamesInThatRating">have played at least 30 rated games in a given rating,</string>
	<string name="havePlayedARatedGameAtLeastOneWeekAgo">have played a rated game within the last week for this rating,</string>
	<string name="ratingDeviationLowerThanXinShogiYinVariants">have a rating deviation lower than %1$s, in standard shogi, and lower than %2$s in variants,</string>
	<string name="beInTopTen">maging parte ng top 10 sa rating na ito.</string>
	<string name="secondRequirementToStopOldPlayersTrustingLeaderboards">The 2nd requirement is so that players who no longer use their accounts stop populating leaderboards.</string>
	<string name="whyAreRatingHigher">Why are ratings different compared to other sites and organisations such as 81Dojo and Shogi Club 24?</string>
	<string name="whyAreRatingHigherExplanation">It is best not to think of ratings as absolute numbers, or compare them against other organisations. Different organisations have different levels of players, different rating systems (Elo, Glicko, Glicko-2, or a modified version of the aforementioned). These factors can drastically affect the absolute numbers (ratings).

It\'s best to think of ratings as \"relative\" figures (as opposed to \"absolute\" figures): Within a pool of players, their relative differences in ratings will help you estimate who will win/draw/lose, and how often. Saying \"I have X rating\" means nothing unless there are other players to compare that rating to.</string>
	<string name="howToHideRatingWhilePlaying">Paano itago ang mga rating habang naglalaro?</string>
	<string name="enableZenMode">Enable Zen-mode in the %1$s, or by pressing %2$s during a game.</string>
	<string name="displayPreferences">ipakita ang mga preperensiya</string>
	<string name="connexionLostCanIGetMyRatingBack">Natalo ako dahil sa lag/pagdiskonekta. Maaari ko ba na mabawi ang aking mga rating points?</string>
	<string name="weCannotDoThatEvenIfItIsServerSideButThatsRare">Sa kasamaang palad, hindi namin maaaring maibalik ang mga rating points na nawala dahil sa lag o pagdiskonekta, kahit man ang problema ay nasa iyong panig o kaya naman ay sa amin. Ngunit, ang ikalawa ay bihirang mangyari. Dapat din tandaan na kapag ang Lishogi ay umulit at natalo ikaw dahil sa nawalang oras, pinawawalang bisa namin ang laro upang maiwasan ang hindi patas na mga pagkakatalo.</string>
	<string name="howToThreeDots">Paano...</string>
	<string name="enableDisableNotificationPopUps">Enable or disable notification popups?</string>
	<string name="viewSiteInformationPopUp">View site information popup</string>
	<string name="lishogiCanOptionnalySendPopUps">Ang Lishogi ay may opsyon na magpadala ng mga popup na mga notipikasyon, halimbawa ay kung ikaw na ang gagalaw o kaya naman ay may nakuha ka na pribadong mensahe.

I-click ang lock icon sa tabi ng lishogi.org na address sa URL bar ng iyong browser.

Pagkatapos ay pumili kung papayagan o i-block ang mga notipikasyon sa Lishogi.</string>
</resources>
