<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="learnShogi">Learn shogi</string>
	<string name="byPlaying">deur te speel!</string>
	<string name="menu">Kieslys</string>
	<string name="progressX">Vordering: %s</string>
	<string name="resetMyProgress">Herstel my vordering</string>
	<string name="youWillLoseAllYourProgress">Jy sal al jou vordering verloor!</string>
	<string name="play">speel!</string>
	<string name="shogiPieces">Shogi pieces</string>
	<string name="theIntroduction">Introduction</string>
	<string name="introBasics">Let\'s learn some basics.</string>
	<string name="introIntro">Your journey begins here.</string>
	<string name="clickHereAfterYouveChosen">Click here or make a move after you\'ve chosen the piece design you like.</string>
	<string name="tellYourPiecesApart">It\'s important that you can tell your pieces apart, so make sure you choose the right piece set.</string>
	<string name="howToSelectPieceSet">How to select your piece set?</string>
	<string name="choosePieceDesign">It\'s important that you can tell your pieces apart, so make sure you choose the right piece set.
To do that click on the cog wheel or your username(top right corner) and then click on \'piece set\'.</string>
	<string name="promotionZone">When some of your pieces reach or leave the first three ranks in your opponent\'s territory you can choose to promote your piece and make it stronger.</string>
	<string name="senteGoesFirst">In shogi the player who goes first is called sente and the player who goes second is called gote. Sente is sometimes represented by black color and gote by white. Make any move as sente to continue.</string>
	<string name="introComplete">You now know some basics, but this part of tutorial is still under construction. For now learn how individual pieces move.</string>
	<string name="introCompleteTwo">You now know some basics! Now learn how individual pieces move.</string>
	<string name="theRook">Die toring</string>
	<string name="itMovesInStraightLines">Hy beweeg in reguit lyne</string>
	<string name="rookIntro">Die toring is \'n sterk stuk. Is jy reg om sy bevelvoerder te wees?</string>
	<string name="rookGoal">Click on the rook to bring it to the star!</string>
	<string name="grabAllTheStarsRemember">Grab all the stars! Remember, look outside of the board.</string>
	<string name="rookPromotion">The rook promotes to the powerful dragon. Don\'t forget that you can also promote your piece when you leave the promotion zone.</string>
	<string name="rookSummary">The rook can go up, down, left or right as much as it wants.</string>
	<string name="dragonSummary">It can move just like the unpromoted rook, but also one square in any diagonal direction, making it much stronger.</string>
	<string name="dragonSummaryTwo">The dragon can move just like the unpromoted rook, but also one square in any diagonal direction, making it much stronger.</string>
	<string name="grabAllTheStars">Gryp al die sterre!</string>
	<string name="theFewerMoves">The fewer moves you make, the more points you win!</string>
	<string name="rookComplete">Geluk! Jy het die werking van die toring suksesvol bemeester.</string>
	<string name="theBishop">Die loper</string>
	<string name="itMovesDiagonally">Hy beweeg diagonaal</string>
	<string name="bishopIntro">Volgende sal ons leer hoe om die loper te manovre!</string>
	<string name="ehThereIsNoPiece">Eh? There is no piece on the board. But look outside the board, a bishop! This area is where the pieces you captured go. You can place the piece back on the board. As usual, grab all the stars.</string>
	<string name="bishopPromotion">Promoting your bishop will make it stronger, it will turn into a piece called \"the horse\".</string>
	<string name="bishopSummary">The bishop moves in any diagonal direction.</string>
	<string name="horseSummary">The promoted bishop moves also diagonally, but it can also go one square up, down, left or right as well.</string>
	<string name="bishopComplete">Welgedaan! Jy is die loper se bevelvoerder.</string>
	<string name="theKing">Die koning</string>
	<string name="theMostImportantPiece">Die belangrikste stuk</string>
	<string name="kingIntro">Jy is die koning. As jy sneuwel, is die wedstryd verlore.</string>
	<string name="theKingIsSlow">The king is rather slow.</string>
	<string name="kingSummary">King can move in any direction, but only by one sqaure.</string>
	<string name="kingComplete">Jy kan nou bevele aan die bevelvoerder gee!</string>
	<string name="theKnight">Die ruiter</string>
	<string name="itMovesInAnLShape">It moves in an L shape, but only FORWARD!</string>
	<string name="knightIntro">Here\'s another challenge for you. The knight is... a tricky piece.</string>
	<string name="knightsHaveAFancyWay">Knights have a fancy way of jumping around!</string>
	<string name="knightsCanJumpOverObstacles">Knights can jump over obstacles!</string>
	<string name="knightSummary">The knight can jump in an L shape forward, but only by two squares forward and one square sideways. Its movement also isn\'t restricted by other pieces - it will just jump over them.</string>
	<string name="pknightSummary">Promoted knight moves are completely different from the unpromoted knight, but you can notice it moves the same as the gold general, so make sure to study that one thoroughly.</string>
	<string name="knightPromotion">The knight can also be promoted. His movements change a lot after that, so pay attention.</string>
	<string name="knightComplete">Knap gedaan! Jy het die ruiter bemeester.</string>
	<string name="thePawn">Die pion</string>
	<string name="itMovesForwardOnly">March forward!</string>
	<string name="pawnIntro">Pionne is swak, maar hulle het groot potensiaal.</string>
	<string name="pawnsMoveOneSquareOnly">Pawns can move to the square directly in front of them, they capture the same way.</string>
	<string name="pawnPromotion">The pawn can also be promoted, the moves are once again the same as the gold general.</string>
	<string name="pawnComplete">Pragtig! Pionne hou geen geheimenisse vir jou nie.</string>
	<string name="pawnSummary">The pawn is a rather straightforward piece to understand.</string>
	<string name="tokinSummary">You should already be familiar with this pattern by now.</string>
	<string name="theLance">The lance</string>
	<string name="itMovesStraightForward">It can go only forward.</string>
	<string name="lanceIntro">Use it wisely.</string>
	<string name="lancesAreStraighforward">Just move forward as much as you can, this should be easy for you.</string>
	<string name="lancePromotion">After the lance is promoted, it moves differently, but you\'ve already seen this somewhere - same as the gold general.</string>
	<string name="lanceSummary">Moves forward, this is really easy.</string>
	<string name="planceSummary">It\'s the same as the gold general.</string>
	<string name="planceSummaryTwo">The promoted lance moves the same as the gold general.</string>
	<string name="lanceComplete">Great job!</string>
	<string name="theGold">The gold general</string>
	<string name="itMovesInAnyDirectionExceptDiagonallyBack">The gold general moves in any direction EXCEPT diagonally back.</string>
	<string name="goldIntro">The gold general movements might be a bit harder to remember at first, but you can surely do it.</string>
	<string name="goldDoesntPromote">The gold general together with the king is the only piece you CAN\'T promote.</string>
	<string name="goldSummary">Try to remember these moves, many pieces move the same after they are promoted.</string>
	<string name="goldComplete">Congratulations! You got this.</string>
	<string name="theSilver">The silver general</string>
	<string name="itMovesEitherForwardOrDiagonallyBack">The silver general moves either forward or diagonally back.</string>
	<string name="silverIntro">Another piece with unusual movements, but this is the last one. Promise!</string>
	<string name="silverPromotion">When you promote the silver general his movements are the same as the gold general.</string>
	<string name="silverSummary">You will surely remember these moves with some practice.</string>
	<string name="psilverSummary">Same as the gold general, you will see this a lot.</string>
	<string name="silverComplete">Congratulations! You are on a roll.</string>
	<string name="promotion">This piece can be promoted.</string>
	<string name="yourPieceReachedThePromotionZone">Your piece reached the promotion zone!</string>
	<string name="itNowPromotesToAStrongerPiece">It can now be promoted to a stronger piece.</string>
	<string name="selectThePieceYouWant">Kies die stuk wat jy wil hê!</string>
	<string name="fundamentals">Beginsels</string>
	<string name="capture">Vat</string>
	<string name="takeTheEnemyPieces">Vat die vyandige stukke</string>
	<string name="captureIntro">Identifiseer die opponent se onverdedigde stukke, en vat hulle!</string>
	<string name="takeTheEnemyPiecesAndDontLoseYours">Take the enemy pieces!
And don\'t lose yours.</string>
	<string name="captureComplete">Congratulations! You know how to fight with shogi pieces!</string>
	<string name="pieceDrops">Piece drops</string>
	<string name="reuseCapturedPieces">Reuse captured pieces!</string>
	<string name="dropIntro">Once again, capture all the opponent\'s pieces, without losing yours!</string>
	<string name="capturedPiecesCanBeDropped">Captured pieces can be dropped back on the board on your turn!</string>
	<string name="dropLimitations">You cannot drop a piece on another piece or drop it where it cannot have any legal moves. Dropping a piece in promotion zone doesn\'t result in promotion.
Take the enemy pieces!</string>
	<string name="youCannotHaveTwoUnpromotedPawns">You cannot have two unpromoted pawns in the same file.</string>
	<string name="protection">Beskerming</string>
	<string name="keepYourPiecesSafe">Hou jou stukke veilig</string>
	<string name="protectionIntro">Identifiseer die stuk wat jou opponent aanval, en verdedig dit!</string>
	<string name="protectionComplete">Baie mooi! \'n Stuk wat jy nie verloor nie, is \'n stuk wat jy wen!</string>
	<string name="escape">Jy is onder aanval!
Ontsnap die bedreiging!</string>
	<string name="noEscape">Daar is geen wegkomkans nie,
maar jy kan verdedig!</string>
	<string name="makeSureAllSafe">Make sure all your pieces are safe!</string>
	<string name="dontForgetYouCanDropToDefend">Don’t forget you can drop pieces to defend!</string>
	<string name="dontLetThemTakeAnyUndefendedPiece">Moenie dat hulle jou onbeskermde stukke vat nie!</string>
	<string name="combat">Stryd</string>
	<string name="captureAndDefendPieces">Vat en verdedig stukke</string>
	<string name="combatIntro">\'n Goeie kryger weet hoe om aan te val en te verdedig!</string>
	<string name="combatComplete">Congratulations! You know how to fight with shogi pieces!</string>
	<string name="checkInOne">Skaak in een</string>
	<string name="attackTheOpponentsKing">Val die opponent se koning aan</string>
	<string name="checkInOneIntro">Om die opponent te skaak, val sy koning aan. Hulle moet dit verdedig!</string>
	<string name="checkInOneGoal">Mik vir die opponent se koning
in een skuif!</string>
	<string name="checkInOneComplete">Jy is \'n ster! Jy het jou opponent geforseer om sy koning te verdedig deur hom te skaak!</string>
	<string name="outOfCheck">Uit skaak uit</string>
	<string name="defendYourKing">Verdedig jou koning</string>
	<string name="outOfCheckIntro">Jy is in skaak! Jy moet ontsnap of die aanval blok.</string>
	<string name="ifYourKingIsAttacked">If your king is attacked, you must deal with the attack.</string>
	<string name="escapeWithTheKing">Ontsnap met die koning!</string>
	<string name="theKingCannotEscapeButBlock">Die koning kan nie ontsnap nie, maar jy kan die aanval blok!</string>
	<string name="youCanGetOutOfCheckByTaking">Jy kan uit skaak uit kom
deur die aanvallende stuk te vat.</string>
	<string name="thisKnightIsCheckingThroughYourDefenses">Die ruiter skaak jou
regdeur jou verdediging!</string>
	<string name="getOutOfCheck">Get out of check!</string>
	<string name="watchOutForYourOpponentsReply">Watch out for your opponent\'s reply!</string>
	<string name="escapeOrBlock">Ontsnap met die koning
of blok die aanval!</string>
	<string name="outOfCheckComplete">Pragtig! Jou koning kan nooit gevat word nie, maak seker jy kan teen \'n skaak verdedig!</string>
	<string name="mateInOne">Mat in een</string>
	<string name="defeatTheOpponentsKing">Oorwin die opponent se koning</string>
	<string name="mateInOneIntro">Jy wen wanneer jou opponent nie homself teen skaak kan verdedig nie.</string>
	<string name="toWinInShogi">To win in shogi, check your opponent\'s king such that they cannot defend. This is mate, or tsume.</string>
	<string name="dropsCommonDeliverMate">Drops are a very common way to deliver mate.</string>
	<string name="attackYourOpponentsKing">Val jou opponent se koning aan
op \'n manier wat nie verdedig kan word nie!</string>
	<string name="chooseYourPieceCarefully">Choose your piece carefully!</string>
	<string name="mateWithADroppedPawnIs">Mate with a dropped pawn is illegal - in a real game you would be forfeited!</string>
	<string name="mateWithAPushedPawnIs">Mate with a pushed pawn is fine.</string>
	<string name="mateInOneComplete">Congratulations! That is how you win shogi games!</string>
	<string name="intermediate">Intermediêr</string>
	<string name="boardSetup">Bord opstelling</string>
	<string name="howTheGameStarts">Hoe die wedstryd begin</string>
	<string name="boardSetupIntro">Die twee weermagte staar mekaar in die oë, reg vir die geveg.</string>
	<string name="thisIsTheInitialPosition">This is the initial position
of every game of shogi!
Make any move to continue.</string>
	<string name="firstPlaceTheKing">There are two traditional ways of setting up pieces before a game. We will be teaching the Oohashi (大橋) style, most commonly used by professionals. The king goes first. Move the king to the back rank’s center square.</string>
	<string name="dropAGold">Drop a gold on the left side of the king, then place another gold on the right.</string>
	<string name="thenPlaceASilver">Then place the silver next to the left-side gold, and a silver beside the right gold.</string>
	<string name="dropTheKnights">Drop the knights the same way you placed the silvers. Your opponent will be doing the Itou (伊藤) style.</string>
	<string name="dropTheLances">Drop the lances. Your opponent will start placing pawns left-to-right before the lances. This is the Itou style.</string>
	<string name="placeTheBishopThenRook">Place the bishop above the left knight, then the rook above the right knight. Of course, in real games there is no need to be in sync with your opponent during setup.</string>
	<string name="placeThePawns">Finally, on the 3rd rank, drop pawns the same way you placed the back rank pieces. The circle will be your guide.</string>
	<string name="pushingThe3rdPawn">Pushing the 3rd pawn to open the bishop’s diagonal is the most common first move. Make this move to continue.</string>
	<string name="boardSetupComplete">Congratulations! You know how to set up the shogi board.</string>
	<string name="repetition">Repetition</string>
	<string name="fourfoldRepetitionIsADrawExcept">Fourfold repetition is a draw, EXCEPT...</string>
	<string name="repetitionIntro">Fourfold repetition is a draw Perpetual check is a loss.</string>
	<string name="ifTheSamePositionOccurs">If the same position occurs 4 times in Shogi, it is an automatic draw. This situation is called sennichite (千日手). Make the only legal move.</string>
	<string name="perpetualCheckIsALoss">But, perpetually checking the opponent’s king is a loss for the checking side. Unfortunately for your opponent, they don’t know! Make the only legal move.</string>
	<string name="boardFlippedFindBestMove">The board was just flipped. What is the best move here?</string>
	<string name="repetitionComplete">The idea behind perpetual check being a loss is to prevent anyone from forcing a draw.</string>
	<string name="advanced">Gevorderd</string>
	<string name="pieceValue">Stuk waarde</string>
	<string name="evaluatePieceStrength">Evalueer stuk sterkte</string>
	<string name="pieceValueIntroNew">Pieces with high mobility have a higher value.
The king is priceless! Losing it means losing the game.</string>
	<string name="queenOverBishop">Vat die stuk
met die hoogste waarde!
Dame &gt; Loper</string>
	<string name="pawnsAreTheLeastValuable">Pawns are the least valuable piece, followed by lances. Knights are slightly more valuable than lances.
Take the most valuable piece.</string>
	<string name="knightSilverGold">Knight &lt; Silver &lt; Gold
Take the most valuable piece without losing your own.</string>
	<string name="goldBishopRook">Gold &lt; Bishop &lt; Rook
Take the most valuable piece.</string>
	<string name="takeAllThePiecesStartingFromTheMost">Take all the pieces in order, starting from the most valuable until the least valuable!</string>
	<string name="anExchangeIs">An exchange is when you capture a piece, and lose another. Which is a better exchange? Silver-for-rook, or gold-for-knight?</string>
	<string name="theOpponentJustGaveAway">The opponent just gave away his valuable rook for free! Do you take it?</string>
	<string name="yourKingsValueIsInfinite">The king\'s value is infinite, compared to a rook. What is the best move here?</string>
	<string name="twoGeneralsAreBetter">Two generals can be worth more than one major piece. A knight and lance can be better than a general. Find a way to sacrifice the bishop and win two generals.</string>
	<string name="rememberWhichPieceIsTheMostValuable">Do you remember which piece is the most valuable?</string>
	<string name="takeThePieceWithTheHighestValue">Vat die stuk
met die hoogste waarde!</string>
	<string name="rememberTheKingIsMoreValuableThanEveryOtherPieceCombined">The king is more valuable than every other piece combined. It may be OK to sacrifice pieces to attack the opponent\'s king. Just don\'t forget your own king\'s safety as well!</string>
	<string name="checkInTwo">Skaak in twee</string>
	<string name="twoMovesToGiveCheck">Twee skuiwe om \'n skaak te gee</string>
	<string name="checkInTwoIntro">Vind die regte kombinasie van twee skuiwe wat die opponent se koning skaak!</string>
	<string name="checkInTwoGoal">Dreig die opponent se koning
in twee skuiwe!</string>
	<string name="checkInTwoComplete">Jy is \'n legende! Jy het jou opponent gedwing om sy koning te beskerm, deur hom te skaak!</string>
	<string name="whatNext">Wat nou?</string>
	<string name="youKnowHowToPlayShogi">You know how to play shogi, congratulations! Do you want to become a stronger player?</string>
	<string name="register">Registreer</string>
	<string name="getAFreeLishogiAccount">Get a free Lishogi account</string>
	<string name="practice">Oefen</string>
	<string name="learnCommonShogiPositions">Learn common shogi positions</string>
	<string name="puzzles">Kopkrappers</string>
	<string name="exerciseYourTacticalSkills">Oefen jou taktiese vermoëns</string>
	<string name="shogiResources">Shogi resources</string>
	<string name="curatedShogiResources">See our curated list of shogi resources</string>
	<string name="videos">Video’s</string>
	<string name="watchInstructiveShogiVideos">Watch instructive shogi videos</string>
	<string name="playPeople">Speel teen mense</string>
	<string name="opponentsFromAroundTheWorld">Opponente van regoor die aarde</string>
	<string name="playMachine">Speel teen rekenaar</string>
	<string name="testYourSkillsWithTheComputer">Oefen jou vaardighede met die rekenaar</string>
	<string name="letsGo">La\'t wiel!</string>
	<string name="stageX">Fase %s</string>
	<string name="awesome">Ongelooflik!</string>
	<string name="excellent">Uitstekend!</string>
	<string name="greatJob">Goeie werk!</string>
	<string name="perfect">Perfek!</string>
	<string name="outstanding">Uitstekend!</string>
	<string name="wayToGo">Knap gedaan!</string>
	<string name="yesYesYes">Spoggerig!</string>
	<string name="youreGoodAtThis">Jy is \'n legende!</string>
	<string name="nailedIt">Mooi skoot.</string>
	<string name="rightOn">Kolskoot!</string>
	<string name="stageXComplete">Fase %s voltooi</string>
	<string name="yourScore">Jou telling</string>
	<string name="next">Volgende</string>
	<string name="backToMenu">Terug na kieslys</string>
	<string name="puzzleFailed">Kopkrapper misluk!</string>
	<string name="retry">Probeer weer</string>
</resources>
