<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="learnShogi">فراگیری شوگی</string>
	<string name="byPlaying">با بازی کردن!</string>
	<string name="menu">منو</string>
	<string name="progressX">پیشرفت: %s</string>
	<string name="resetMyProgress">تنظیم مجدد پیشرفت من</string>
	<string name="youWillLoseAllYourProgress">شما همه پیشرفت خود را از دست خواهید داد!</string>
	<string name="play">بازی کن!</string>
	<string name="shogiPieces">مهره های شوگی</string>
	<string name="theIntroduction">مقدمه ای بر شوگی</string>
	<string name="introBasics">یادگیری برخی اصول پایه</string>
	<string name="introIntro">سفر شما از اینجا آغاز میشود.</string>
	<string name="clickHereAfterYouveChosen">پس از انتخاب مهره مورد نظر خود،اینجا کلیک کنید.</string>
	<string name="tellYourPiecesApart">It\'s important that you can tell your pieces apart, so make sure you choose the right piece set.</string>
	<string name="howToSelectPieceSet">How to select your piece set?</string>
	<string name="choosePieceDesign">مهم است بتوانید مهره های خود را از هم تشخیص دهید، پس با دقت ست مهره را انتخاب کنید.
برای انجام این کار، روی چرخ دنده یا نام کاربری خود (گوشه سمت راست بالا) کلیک کنید و سپس بر روی \"ست مهرها\" کلیک کنید.</string>
	<string name="promotionZone">هنگامی که یکی از مهره های شما به سه رتبه اول در قلمرو حریف خود می رسند یا به انجا رسیده و آنجا را ترک میکنند، می توانید انتخاب کنید که مهره خود را ارتقا دهید و آن را قوی تر کنید.</string>
	<string name="senteGoesFirst">در شوگی بازیکنی که اولین حرکت را انجام می‌دهد سنتِ(sente) می‌گویند و بازیکنی که بعد از سنتِ بازی میکند گُتِ(gote) میگویند. بازیکن اول به رنگ سیاه و بازیکن دوم به رنگ سفید نمایش داده میشوند.برای ادامه حرکتی با مهره sente انجام دهید.</string>
	<string name="introComplete">کنون مقداری از اصول را فراگرفتید، اما این قسمت آموزشی همچنان نیازمند توسعه بیشتری است.لطفاً به فراگیری حرکات مهره ها بپردازید.</string>
	<string name="introCompleteTwo">You now know some basics! Now learn how individual pieces move.</string>
	<string name="theRook">رخ</string>
	<string name="itMovesInStraightLines">در خط های مستقیم حرکت میکند</string>
	<string name="rookIntro">رخ مهره قوییه. آماده ای که بهش دستور بدی؟</string>
	<string name="rookGoal">روی رخ کلیک کن
تا روی ستاره ببریش!</string>
	<string name="grabAllTheStarsRemember">Grab all the stars! Remember, look outside of the board.</string>
	<string name="rookPromotion">The rook promotes to the powerful dragon. Don\'t forget that you can also promote your piece when you leave the promotion zone.</string>
	<string name="rookSummary">The rook can go up, down, left or right as much as it wants.</string>
	<string name="dragonSummary">It can move just like the unpromoted rook, but also one square in any diagonal direction, making it much stronger.</string>
	<string name="dragonSummaryTwo">The dragon can move just like the unpromoted rook, but also one square in any diagonal direction, making it much stronger.</string>
	<string name="grabAllTheStars">همه ستاره ها رو بگیر!</string>
	<string name="theFewerMoves">هرچی تعداد حرکت کمتری بری،
ستاره بیشتری میگیری!</string>
	<string name="rookComplete">تبریک! شما با موفقیت در بازی با رخ استاد شدید.</string>
	<string name="theBishop">فیل</string>
	<string name="itMovesDiagonally">مورب حرکت میکنه</string>
	<string name="bishopIntro">در مرحله بعدی یاد میگیریم که چگونه با فیل مانور دهیم!</string>
	<string name="ehThereIsNoPiece">Eh? There is no piece on the board. But look outside the board, a bishop! This area is where the pieces you captured go. You can place the piece back on the board. As usual, grab all the stars.</string>
	<string name="bishopPromotion">Promoting your bishop will make it stronger, it will turn into a piece called \"the horse\".</string>
	<string name="bishopSummary">The bishop moves in any diagonal direction.</string>
	<string name="horseSummary">The promoted bishop moves also diagonally, but it can also go one square up, down, left or right as well.</string>
	<string name="bishopComplete">تبریک! شما میتوانید یک فیل را فرمانروایی کنید.</string>
	<string name="theKing">شاه</string>
	<string name="theMostImportantPiece">مهم ترین مهره شطرنج</string>
	<string name="kingIntro">شما شاه هستید. اگه وارد جنگ شوید،باختید.</string>
	<string name="theKingIsSlow">شاه کُنده.</string>
	<string name="kingSummary">King can move in any direction, but only by one sqaure.</string>
	<string name="kingComplete">حالا شما میتوانید فرمانده را فرمانروایی کنید!</string>
	<string name="theKnight">اسب</string>
	<string name="itMovesInAnLShape">به صورت L حرکت میکند</string>
	<string name="knightIntro">چالشی برای شما. اسب... مهره فریبنده ایه.</string>
	<string name="knightsHaveAFancyWay">اسب میتواند به صورت فریبنده به اطراف بپرد!</string>
	<string name="knightsCanJumpOverObstacles">اسب میتونه از روی مانع ها بپره!
فرار کن و ستاره ها رو بگیر!</string>
	<string name="knightSummary">The knight can jump in an L shape forward, but only by two squares forward and one square sideways. Its movement also isn\'t restricted by other pieces - it will just jump over them.</string>
	<string name="pknightSummary">Promoted knight moves are completely different from the unpromoted knight, but you can notice it moves the same as the gold general, so make sure to study that one thoroughly.</string>
	<string name="knightPromotion">The knight can also be promoted. His movements change a lot after that, so pay attention.</string>
	<string name="knightComplete">تبریک! شما در بازی با اسب استاد شدید.</string>
	<string name="thePawn">پیاده</string>
	<string name="itMovesForwardOnly">فقط به جلو حرکت میکند</string>
	<string name="pawnIntro">پیاده ها ضعیفن، اما کوله باری از پتانسیل اند.</string>
	<string name="pawnsMoveOneSquareOnly">پیاده ها فقط یک خونه حرکت میکنند.
اما وقتی که به اون طرف صفحه برسند، مهره قویی میشن!</string>
	<string name="pawnPromotion">ارتقاء پیاده</string>
	<string name="pawnComplete">تبریک! هیچ رازی از پیاده ها بر شما پنهان نیست.</string>
	<string name="pawnSummary">The pawn is a rather straightforward piece to understand.</string>
	<string name="tokinSummary">You should already be familiar with this pattern by now.</string>
	<string name="theLance">The lance</string>
	<string name="itMovesStraightForward">It can go only forward.</string>
	<string name="lanceIntro">Use it wisely.</string>
	<string name="lancesAreStraighforward">Just move forward as much as you can, this should be easy for you.</string>
	<string name="lancePromotion">After the lance is promoted, it moves differently, but you\'ve already seen this somewhere - same as the gold general.</string>
	<string name="lanceSummary">Moves forward, this is really easy.</string>
	<string name="planceSummary">It\'s the same as the gold general.</string>
	<string name="planceSummaryTwo">The promoted lance moves the same as the gold general.</string>
	<string name="lanceComplete">Great job!</string>
	<string name="theGold">The gold general</string>
	<string name="itMovesInAnyDirectionExceptDiagonallyBack">The gold general moves in any direction EXCEPT diagonally back.</string>
	<string name="goldIntro">The gold general movements might be a bit harder to remember at first, but you can surely do it.</string>
	<string name="goldDoesntPromote">The gold general together with the king is the only piece you CAN\'T promote.</string>
	<string name="goldSummary">Try to remember these moves, many pieces move the same after they are promoted.</string>
	<string name="goldComplete">Congratulations! You got this.</string>
	<string name="theSilver">The silver general</string>
	<string name="itMovesEitherForwardOrDiagonallyBack">The silver general moves either forward or diagonally back.</string>
	<string name="silverIntro">Another piece with unusual movements, but this is the last one. Promise!</string>
	<string name="silverPromotion">When you promote the silver general his movements are the same as the gold general.</string>
	<string name="silverSummary">You will surely remember these moves with some practice.</string>
	<string name="psilverSummary">Same as the gold general, you will see this a lot.</string>
	<string name="silverComplete">Congratulations! You are on a roll.</string>
	<string name="promotion">This piece can be promoted.</string>
	<string name="yourPieceReachedThePromotionZone">Your piece reached the promotion zone!</string>
	<string name="itNowPromotesToAStrongerPiece">حالا به یک مهره قوی تر ارتقاء میابه.</string>
	<string name="selectThePieceYouWant">مهره ای که میخواهید را انتخاب کنید!</string>
	<string name="fundamentals">اصول</string>
	<string name="capture">زدن</string>
	<string name="takeTheEnemyPieces">مهره حریف رو بزن</string>
	<string name="captureIntro">مهره های بی دفاع حریف را شناسایی کنید، و آن ها را بزنید!</string>
	<string name="takeTheEnemyPiecesAndDontLoseYours">Take the enemy pieces!
And don\'t lose yours.</string>
	<string name="captureComplete">تبریک! شما می دانید چگونه با مهره های شطرنج بجنگید!</string>
	<string name="pieceDrops">Piece drops</string>
	<string name="reuseCapturedPieces">Reuse captured pieces!</string>
	<string name="dropIntro">Once again, capture all the opponent\'s pieces, without losing yours!</string>
	<string name="capturedPiecesCanBeDropped">Captured pieces can be dropped back on the board on your turn!</string>
	<string name="dropLimitations">You cannot drop a piece on another piece or drop it where it cannot have any legal moves. Dropping a piece in promotion zone doesn\'t result in promotion.
Take the enemy pieces!</string>
	<string name="youCannotHaveTwoUnpromotedPawns">You cannot have two unpromoted pawns in the same file.</string>
	<string name="protection">محافظت</string>
	<string name="keepYourPiecesSafe">مهره های خود را امن نگه دارید</string>
	<string name="protectionIntro">مهره هایی که حریفتان حمله میکند را شناسایی کنید، و از آن ها دفاع کنید!</string>
	<string name="protectionComplete">تبریک! مهره ای که شما از دست ندادی مهره ای است که شما بردید!</string>
	<string name="escape">شما مورد حمله قرار گرفتید!
از تهدید فرار کنید!</string>
	<string name="noEscape">هیچ راه فراری نیست،
اما میتوانید دفاع کنید!</string>
	<string name="makeSureAllSafe">Make sure all your pieces are safe!</string>
	<string name="dontForgetYouCanDropToDefend">Don’t forget you can drop pieces to defend!</string>
	<string name="dontLetThemTakeAnyUndefendedPiece">بهشون اجازه نده هیچ مهره بی دفاعی رو بگیرن!</string>
	<string name="combat">مبارزه</string>
	<string name="captureAndDefendPieces">زدن و دفاع کردن مهره ها</string>
	<string name="combatIntro">یه جنگجوی خوب هم حمله بلده هم دفاع!</string>
	<string name="combatComplete">تبریک! شما بلدید چطور با مهره های شطرنج بجنگید!</string>
	<string name="checkInOne">کیش در یک حرکت</string>
	<string name="attackTheOpponentsKing">به شاه حریف حمله کن</string>
	<string name="checkInOneIntro">برای کیش دادن به حریف، به شاهش حمله کن. اون باید دفاع کنه!</string>
	<string name="checkInOneGoal">شاه حریف را در یک حرکت هدف بگیر!</string>
	<string name="checkInOneComplete">تبریک میگم! شما حریف خود را کیش دادید و مجبور به دفاع از شاه خود!</string>
	<string name="outOfCheck">خارج از کیش</string>
	<string name="defendYourKing">از شاهت دفاع کن</string>
	<string name="outOfCheckIntro">شما دارد در کیش قرار دارید و یا باید فرار و یا از حمله جلوگیری کنید.</string>
	<string name="ifYourKingIsAttacked">If your king is attacked, you must deal with the attack.</string>
	<string name="escapeWithTheKing">فرار با شاه!</string>
	<string name="theKingCannotEscapeButBlock">شاه نمی تواند فرار کند اما شما می توانید حمله را بلاک کنید!</string>
	<string name="youCanGetOutOfCheckByTaking">شما می توانید با زدن مهره ای که شما را کیش کرده، از کیش خارج شوید.</string>
	<string name="thisKnightIsCheckingThroughYourDefenses">This knight is checking
through your defences!</string>
	<string name="getOutOfCheck">Get out of check!</string>
	<string name="watchOutForYourOpponentsReply">Watch out for your opponent\'s reply!</string>
	<string name="escapeOrBlock">یا شاهت رو فراری بده، و یا حمله رو بلاک کن!</string>
	<string name="outOfCheckComplete">Congratulations! Your king can never be taken, make sure you can defend against a check!</string>
	<string name="mateInOne">مات در یک حرکت</string>
	<string name="defeatTheOpponentsKing">شاه حریف را شکست بده</string>
	<string name="mateInOneIntro">شما زمانی برنده می شوید که حریفتان در برابر کیش نمی تواند از خودش دفاع کند.</string>
	<string name="toWinInShogi">To win in shogi, check your opponent\'s king such that they cannot defend. This is mate, or tsume.</string>
	<string name="dropsCommonDeliverMate">Drops are a very common way to deliver mate.</string>
	<string name="attackYourOpponentsKing">Attack your opponent\'s king
in a way that cannot be defended!</string>
	<string name="chooseYourPieceCarefully">Choose your piece carefully!</string>
	<string name="mateWithADroppedPawnIs">Mate with a dropped pawn is illegal - in a real game you would be forfeited!</string>
	<string name="mateWithAPushedPawnIs">Mate with a pushed pawn is fine.</string>
	<string name="mateInOneComplete">تبریک میگم! این گونه شما در بازی شطرنج برنده می شوید!</string>
	<string name="intermediate">متوسط</string>
	<string name="boardSetup">چبدمان صفحه</string>
	<string name="howTheGameStarts">چگونه بازی شروع می شود</string>
	<string name="boardSetupIntro">The two armies face each other, ready for the battle.</string>
	<string name="thisIsTheInitialPosition">This is the initial position
of every game of chess!
Make any move to continue.</string>
	<string name="firstPlaceTheKing">There are two traditional ways of setting up pieces before a game. We will be teaching the Oohashi (大橋) style, most commonly used by professionals. The king goes first. Move the king to the back rank’s center square.</string>
	<string name="dropAGold">Drop a gold on the left side of the king, then place another gold on the right.</string>
	<string name="thenPlaceASilver">Then place the silver next to the left-side gold, and a silver beside the right gold.</string>
	<string name="dropTheKnights">Drop the knights the same way you placed the silvers. Your opponent will be doing the Itou (伊藤) style.</string>
	<string name="dropTheLances">Drop the lances. Your opponent will start placing pawns left-to-right before the lances. This is the Itou style.</string>
	<string name="placeTheBishopThenRook">Place the bishop above the left knight, then the rook above the right knight. Of course, in real games there is no need to be in sync with your opponent during setup.</string>
	<string name="placeThePawns">Finally, on the 3rd rank, drop pawns the same way you placed the back rank pieces. The circle will be your guide.</string>
	<string name="pushingThe3rdPawn">Pushing the 3rd pawn to open the bishop’s diagonal is the most common first move. Make this move to continue.</string>
	<string name="boardSetupComplete">Congratulations! You know how to set up the chess board.</string>
	<string name="repetition">Repetition</string>
	<string name="fourfoldRepetitionIsADrawExcept">Fourfold repetition is a draw, EXCEPT...</string>
	<string name="repetitionIntro">Fourfold repetition is a draw Perpetual check is a loss.</string>
	<string name="ifTheSamePositionOccurs">If the same position occurs 4 times in Shogi, it is an automatic draw. This situation is called sennichite (千日手). Make the only legal move.</string>
	<string name="perpetualCheckIsALoss">But, perpetually checking the opponent’s king is a loss for the checking side. Unfortunately for your opponent, they don’t know! Make the only legal move.</string>
	<string name="boardFlippedFindBestMove">The board was just flipped. What is the best move here?</string>
	<string name="repetitionComplete">The idea behind perpetual check being a loss is to prevent anyone from forcing a draw.</string>
	<string name="advanced">Advanced</string>
	<string name="pieceValue">Piece value</string>
	<string name="evaluatePieceStrength">Evaluate piece strength</string>
	<string name="pieceValueIntroNew">Pieces with high mobility have a higher value.
The king is priceless! Losing it means losing the game.</string>
	<string name="queenOverBishop">Take the piece
with the highest value!
Queen &gt; Bishop</string>
	<string name="pawnsAreTheLeastValuable">Pawns are the least valuable piece, followed by lances. Knights are slightly more valuable than lances.
Take the most valuable piece.</string>
	<string name="knightSilverGold">Knight &lt; Silver &lt; Gold
Take the most valuable piece without losing your own.</string>
	<string name="goldBishopRook">Gold &lt; Bishop &lt; Rook
Take the most valuable piece.</string>
	<string name="takeAllThePiecesStartingFromTheMost">Take all the pieces in order, starting from the most valuable until the least valuable!</string>
	<string name="anExchangeIs">An exchange is when you capture a piece, and lose another. Which is a better exchange? Silver-for-rook, or gold-for-knight?</string>
	<string name="theOpponentJustGaveAway">The opponent just gave away his valuable rook for free! Do you take it?</string>
	<string name="yourKingsValueIsInfinite">The king\'s value is infinite, compared to a rook. What is the best move here?</string>
	<string name="twoGeneralsAreBetter">Two generals can be worth more than one major piece. A knight and lance can be better than a general. Find a way to sacrifice the bishop and win two generals.</string>
	<string name="rememberWhichPieceIsTheMostValuable">Do you remember which piece is the most valuable?</string>
	<string name="takeThePieceWithTheHighestValue">با ارزش ترین مهره را بزن!</string>
	<string name="rememberTheKingIsMoreValuableThanEveryOtherPieceCombined">The king is more valuable than every other piece combined. It may be OK to sacrifice pieces to attack the opponent\'s king. Just don\'t forget your own king\'s safety as well!</string>
	<string name="checkInTwo">کیس در دو حرکت</string>
	<string name="twoMovesToGiveCheck">Two moves to give a check</string>
	<string name="checkInTwoIntro">Find the right combination of two moves that checks the opponent\'s king!</string>
	<string name="checkInTwoGoal">به شاه حریف در دو حرکت حمله کنید!</string>
	<string name="checkInTwoComplete">تبریک! شما به شاه حریف کیش دادید و حریف را مجبور به دفاع از شاه خود کردید!</string>
	<string name="whatNext">گام بعدی چیست؟</string>
	<string name="youKnowHowToPlayShogi">You know how to play shogi, congratulations! Do you want to become a stronger player?</string>
	<string name="register">نام نویسی</string>
	<string name="getAFreeLishogiAccount">یک حساب کاربری رایگان در لیچس دریافت کنید</string>
	<string name="practice">تمرین</string>
	<string name="learnCommonShogiPositions">Learn common shogi positions</string>
	<string name="puzzles">معما</string>
	<string name="exerciseYourTacticalSkills">Exercise your tactical skills</string>
	<string name="shogiResources">Shogi resources</string>
	<string name="curatedShogiResources">See our curated list of shogi resources</string>
	<string name="videos">ویدیو ها</string>
	<string name="watchInstructiveShogiVideos">Watch instructive shogi videos</string>
	<string name="playPeople">با مردم بازی کنید</string>
	<string name="opponentsFromAroundTheWorld">Opponents from around the world</string>
	<string name="playMachine">Play machine</string>
	<string name="testYourSkillsWithTheComputer">Test your skills with the computer</string>
	<string name="letsGo">Let\'s go!</string>
	<string name="stageX">Stage %s</string>
	<string name="awesome">Awesome!</string>
	<string name="excellent">Excellent!</string>
	<string name="greatJob">Great job!</string>
	<string name="perfect">Perfect!</string>
	<string name="outstanding">فوق العاده!</string>
	<string name="wayToGo">Way to go!</string>
	<string name="yesYesYes">Yes, yes, yes!</string>
	<string name="youreGoodAtThis">You\'re good at this!</string>
	<string name="nailedIt">Nailed it.</string>
	<string name="rightOn">Right on!</string>
	<string name="stageXComplete">Stage %s complete</string>
	<string name="yourScore">Your score</string>
	<string name="next">بعدی</string>
	<string name="backToMenu">برگشت به منو</string>
	<string name="puzzleFailed">Puzzle failed!</string>
	<string name="retry">تلاش مجدد</string>
</resources>
