<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <string name="arena">Arena</string>
  <string name="arenaTournaments">Arena tournaments</string>
  <string name="isItRated">Is it rated?</string>
  <string name="willBeNotified">You will be notified when the tournament starts, so feel free to leave this tab idle.</string>
  <string name="isRated">This tournament is rated and will affect your rating.</string>
  <string name="isNotRated">This tournament is *not* rated and will *not* affect your rating.</string>
  <string name="someRated">Some tournaments are rated and will affect your rating.</string>
  <string name="howAreScoresCalculated">How are scores calculated?</string>
  <string name="howAreScoresCalculatedAnswer">A win has a base score of 2 points, a draw 1 point, and a loss is worth no points.
If you win two games consecutively you will start a double-point streak, represented by a flame icon.
The following games will continue to be worth double points until you fail to win a game.
That is, a win will be worth 4 points, a draw 2 points and a loss will still not award any points.

For example, two wins followed by a draw will be worth 6 points: 2 + 2 + (2 x 1)</string>
  <string name="berserk">Arena Berserk</string>
  <string name="berserkAnswer">When a player clicks the Berserk button at the beginning of the game, they lose half of their clock time, but the win is worth one extra tournament point.

Going Berserk in time controls with an increment also cancels the increment (1+2 is an exception, it gives 1+0).

Berserk is not available for games with zero initial time (0+1, 0+2).

Berserk only grants an extra point if you play at least 7 moves in the game.</string>
  <string name="howIsTheWinnerDecided">How is the winner decided?</string>
  <string name="howIsTheWinnerDecidedAnswer">The player(s) with the most points after the tournament's set time limit will be announced the winner(s).

When two or more players have the same number of points, the tournament performance is the tie break.</string>
  <string name="howDoesPairingWork">How does the pairing work?</string>
  <string name="howDoesPairingWorkAnswer">At the beginning of the tournament, players are paired based on their rating.
As soon as you finish a game, return to the tournament lobby: you will then be paired with a player close to your ranking. This ensures minimum wait time, however, you may not face all other players in the tournament.
Play fast and return to the lobby to play more games and win more points.</string>
  <string name="howDoesItEnd">How does it end?</string>
  <string name="howDoesItEndAnswer">The tournament has a countdown clock. When it reaches zero, the tournament rankings are frozen, and the winner is announced. Games in progress must be finished, however, they don't count for the tournament.</string>
  <string name="otherRules">Other important rules</string>
  <string name="thereIsACountdown">There is a countdown for your first move. Failing to make a move within this time will forfeit the game to your opponent.</string>
  <plurals name="drawingWithinNbMoves">
    <item quantity="one">Drawing the game within the first %s move will earn neither player any points.</item>
    <item quantity="other">Drawing the game within the first %s moves will earn neither player any points.</item>
  </plurals>
  <string name="thisIsPrivate">This is a private tournament</string>
  <string name="shareUrl">Share this URL to let people join: %s</string>
  <string name="drawStreakStandard">Draw streaks: When a player has consecutive draws in an arena, only the first draw will result in a point or draws lasting more than %s moves in standard games. The draw streak can only be broken by a win, not a loss or a draw.</string>
  <string name="drawStreakVariants">The minimum game length for drawn games to award points differs by variant. The table below lists the threshold for each variant.</string>
  <string name="variant">Variant</string>
  <string name="minimumGameLength">Minimum game length</string>
  <string name="history">Arena History</string>
  <plurals name="viewAllXTeams" comment="viewAllXTeams [one] [other]&#10;&#10;%s is the number of teams that can be viewed">
    <item quantity="one">View the team</item>
    <item quantity="other">View all %s teams</item>
  </plurals>
  <string name="newTeamBattle">New Team Battle</string>
  <string name="customStartDate">Custom start date</string>
  <string name="customStartDateHelp">In your own local timezone. This overrides the "Time before tournament starts" setting</string>
  <string name="allowBerserk">Allow Berserk</string>
  <string name="allowBerserkHelp">Let players halve their clock time to gain an extra point</string>
  <string name="allowChatHelp">Let players discuss in a chat room</string>
  <string name="arenaStreaks">Arena streaks</string>
  <string name="arenaStreaksHelp">After 2 wins, consecutive wins grant 4 points instead of 2.</string>
  <string name="noBerserkAllowed">No Berserk allowed</string>
  <string name="noArenaStreaks">No Arena streaks</string>
  <string name="averagePerformance">Average performance</string>
  <string name="averageScore">Average score</string>
  <string name="myTournaments">My tournaments</string>
  <string name="editTournament">Edit tournament</string>
  <string name="editTeamBattle">Edit team battle</string>
  <string name="defender">Defender</string>
  <string name="pickYourTeam">Pick your team</string>
  <string name="whichTeamWillYouRepresentInThisBattle">Which team will you represent in this battle?</string>
  <string name="youMustJoinOneOfTheseTeamsToParticipate">You must join one of these teams to participate!</string>
  <string name="created">Created</string>
  <string name="recentlyPlayed">Recently played</string>
  <string name="bestResults">Best results</string>
  <string name="tournamentStats">Tournament stats</string>
  <string name="rankAvgHelp">The rank average is a percentage of your ranking. Lower is better.

For instance, being ranked 3 in a tournament of 100 players = 3%. Being ranked 10 in a tournament of 1000 players = 1%.</string>
  <string name="medians">medians</string>
  <string name="allAveragesAreX">All averages on this page are %s.</string>
  <string name="total">Total</string>
  <string name="pointsAvg">Points average</string>
  <string name="pointsSum">Points sum</string>
  <string name="rankAvg">Rank average</string>
  <string name="tournamentWinners">Tournament winners</string>
  <string name="tournamentShields">Tournament shields</string>
  <string name="onlyTitled">Only titled players</string>
  <string name="onlyTitledHelp">Require an official title to join the tournament</string>
  <string name="tournamentPairingsAreNowClosed">The tournament pairings are now closed.</string>
  <string name="berserkRate">Berserk rate</string>
</resources>
